<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>tag:x,2008-06-01:kind/x</id>
  <link href="http://localhost:3000" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <link href="http://localhost:3000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <title>Go Free Range Blog</title>
  <updated>2018-04-06T17:38:30+01:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-04-06:/week-481</id>
    <published>2018-04-06T17:38:30+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-06T17:38:30+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-481" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 481</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-roos</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-481"&gt;Week 481&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;Afternoon folks.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It’s a beautiful day here today: it finally feels a bit like Spring after some very cold and wet days.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; rejoined us on Tuesday after his week away and after we’d all enjoyed the long Easter weekend break.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We spent Tuesday and Wednesday working on the GDS &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/asset-manager"&gt;Asset Manager&lt;/a&gt; project before finally finishing up and handing over yesterday. I have slightly mixed feelings about handing it over: having a break from the work is very welcome but I’m disappointed that we didn’t get as much done as we’d have liked. Unfortunately the budget wouldn’t allow us to continue but I’m hopeful that we’ve done a good enough job of documenting what we’ve done so that the GOV.UK team can continue the work to get the remaining &lt;a href="http://github.com/alphagov/whitehall"&gt;Whitehall&lt;/a&gt; attachments served by Asset Manager.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Our other big news of the week is that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/beng"&gt;Ben Griffiths&lt;/a&gt; has joined us as our newest member. James and I have both worked with Ben in the past (James and Ben at &lt;a href="https://www.thoughtworks.com/"&gt;Thoughtworks&lt;/a&gt; and James, Ben and I at &lt;a href="https://www.reevoo.com/"&gt;Reevoo&lt;/a&gt;) and he’s been a friend of GFR since the beginning. Since leaving Reevoo Ben’s been involved in numerous startups and has most recently been working at &lt;a href="https://www.dxw.com/"&gt;DXW&lt;/a&gt;. We’re all really happy to have Ben join and are looking forward to seeing what this means for us.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben’s official start date is today but we’ve all agreed to take it a bit easier today and to welcome Ben properly on Monday.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Until next time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– Chris&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-03-29:/week-480</id>
    <published>2018-03-29T17:38:41+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-29T17:38:41+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-480" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 480</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-roos</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-480"&gt;Week 480&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;Howdi folks&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; is taking a well-earned break this week. &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-lowis"&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; and I have worked from &lt;a href="http://www.theofficegroup.co.uk/"&gt;TOG&lt;/a&gt; Whitechapel, TOG Bloomsbury and from home.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Looking at the office in Hoxton last week made us wonder what else was available. A friend suggested we look at &lt;a href="http://www.ministryofstartups.com/"&gt;Ministry of Startups&lt;/a&gt;. We got in touch and were able to view a couple of their Whitechapel properties on Monday. The offices look just about perfect for what we’re after and they’re &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; competitively priced so we’re planning to take one on. We’ve notified TOG that we’d like to cancel our memberships.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’re coming to the end of our time on the &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/asset-manager"&gt;Asset Manager&lt;/a&gt; project and have a final handover session arranged for Thursday next week. We ran the metadata update in production earlier this week but then suffered a number of setbacks that have further delayed us being able to switch to serving &lt;a href="http://github.com/alphagov/whitehall"&gt;Whitehall&lt;/a&gt; attachments from Asset Manager. We’ll have to see how much we can do on Tuesday and Wednesday before the handover.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris published the &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-42"&gt;write-up of our Show &amp;amp; Tell event from last week&lt;/a&gt; as well as &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/week-479"&gt;weeknotes for last week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris also helped get the &lt;a href="https://community.coops.tech/t/cotech-newsletter-march-2018/685"&gt;CoTech March newsletter&lt;/a&gt; published.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’ve ordered a laptop for our new member. He joins us on the 6th of April so we’ll be able to share who it is next week.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Harmonia chose me to donate to charity this month and I chose &lt;a href="https://www.nct.org.uk/"&gt;NCT&lt;/a&gt;. My partner and I are expecting our first child and have been making use of the great NCT classes available.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Until next time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– Chris&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-03-29:/week-477</id>
    <published>2018-03-29T15:55:35+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-29T15:55:35+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-477" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 477</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-lowis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-477"&gt;Week 477&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;I returned from an extended trip to Colombia this week and in my jet-lagged state never got round to writing weeknotes. These come to you, therefore, almost 3 weeks late!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Looking back through my notes I see we spent a couple of days in the Bloomsbury Office Group office, held our monthly drinks at The Three Crowns and continued to work on our Asset Manager project for GDS.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="asset-manager"&gt;Asset Manager&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We are trying to move the last remaining files (around 500,000 attachments) from the Whitehall publishing application to Asset Manager. In doing so we need to make sure that Whitehall no longer depends on files existing on the file system as once we’ve made the switch the files will leave in Amazon’s cloud storage service S3.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One area we’d overlooked was the functionality to preview a CSV which is used to give an overview of data files before a user commits to downloading a potentially large file. For very large files the code was using ruby’s low-level &lt;code&gt;File&lt;/code&gt; API to read in a limited number of bytes of the file from disk. &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/whitehall/pull/3826"&gt;We changed this to use a HTTP RANGE request instead&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We also had to make sure that metadata about each attachment that was previously stored in Whitehall is now stored in Asset Manager. This includes &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/asset-manager/pull/502"&gt;support for parent document URLs in HTTP headers&lt;/a&gt;. In addition we &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/asset-manager/pull/512"&gt;continued to add support&lt;/a&gt; for access-limited and draft assets to Asset Manager.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Warm greetings from the future!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;!-- add content here --&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-03-29:/week-479</id>
    <published>2018-03-29T15:42:39+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-29T15:42:39+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-479" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 479</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-lowis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-479"&gt;Week 479&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;This week we were mostly finishing up our work on the Asset Manager project. We took some time away from that to do a little bit of office-hunting and to do our quarterly “away-day”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="asset-management"&gt;Asset Management&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We were mostly preparing to switch serving attachments from Whitehall to Asset Manager by:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/whitehall/pull/3881"&gt;Refactoring the related controllers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/whitehall/pull/3892"&gt;Writing a worker&lt;/a&gt; to handle the migration of metadata&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/whitehall/pull/3903"&gt;Landing a few changes&lt;/a&gt; from a long-running branch onto &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/whitehall/pull/3880"&gt;Dealing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/asset-manager/pull/528"&gt;with&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/asset-manager/pull/531"&gt;edge cases&lt;/a&gt; present in the 500,000 assets we’re attempting to migrate.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;By the end of the week we’d reached the point where we could start running the migration to make sure that all of the assets in Asset Manager had the same draft, redirect and access-limited metadata as they do in Whitehall. Once we’ve ironed out all the inconsistencies we’ll finally make a change to the nginx server and start serving traffic.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="office-hunting"&gt;Office Hunting&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We have a new member joining in early April which will take Go Free Range up to 4 permanent members. We’re currently using co-working membership at The Office Group. While we’ve been happy with the flexibility this offers there’s a couple of downsides that will get worse when we’re 4. Firstly, it’s quite difficult to find 4 desks next to each other in our preferred co-working space. This is understandable, they’re really designed for individual workers not teams. Secondly, at £375 per desk per month it starts to look financially more sensible to look for some permanent desks somewhere.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We certainly miss having our own office - we used to be able to host people for short stays working with us, have clients over, and host evening events in our old place on Worship St. With rents steadily climbing though, this may not be possible again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This week we took a look at some sub-let desks in a spacious building in Hoxton. We’re going to keep looking for something flexible and keep thinking about a slightly more permanent home for the future.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="away-day"&gt;Away Day&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We like to get away from the day-to-day work once every 3 months ago and talk about something a bit higher level. This time we spent a couple of hours in a The Office Group meeting room near Bank station, before having a long lunch. On the agenda was our pay and renumeration for the next financial year, our on-going work to change our articles of association and become a legit co-operative and our hopes and aspirations for the coming year with a new member joining.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A particularly interesting discussion was around time-tracking and holidays. We have an informal “take as many days off as you need” policy, but we’re a little worried that we’re not taking the breaks we need when we’re busy, and that without a firmer policy we might be feeling guilty taking time off when others are not. We discussed tracking time worked and time off more closely but felt unsure about the unintended consequences of doing that. We decided to have a standing agenda item in our weekly meetings where we talk about time worked, time taken off, what our work-life balance is like and anything we can change to improve it. We hope that by forcing ourselves to discuss this more regularly it’ll be easier to make small changes to improve things.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;‘Til next time!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;!-- add content here --&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-03-28:/show-and-tell-42</id>
    <published>2018-03-28T21:05:41+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-28T21:05:41+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-42" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Show and Tell 42</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-lowis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="show-and-tell-42"&gt;Show and Tell 42&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; and I were joined by &lt;a href="http://codon.com/"&gt;Tom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/beng"&gt;Ben&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://chris.patuzzo.co.uk/"&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; and first-time show-and-teller &lt;a href="https://github.com/tomclose"&gt;Tom&lt;/a&gt; for our 42nd Show &amp;amp; Tell evening.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="yubikey"&gt;Yubikey&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris has recently taken on a role at work that involves greater access to production systems. His team’s use of &lt;a href="https://www.yubico.com/"&gt;Yubikey’s&lt;/a&gt; as part of their approach to security prompted Chris to simplify and harden the security around all his passwords and sensitive data.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Yubikey offers &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi-factor_authentication"&gt;2-factor authentication&lt;/a&gt; by being “something you have” alongside “something you know” (Chris memorises a password). There are various types of Yubikey available. Chris showed us the USB-C version which works with recent Macbooks. There’s also an NFC version which would work with some laptops and smartphones.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris then went on to explain how the Yubikey fits into the system he now uses to secure all of his accounts and sensitive documents.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/chris_p_authentication.jpeg" alt="A photograph of a whiteboard diagram of Chris's authentication system" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris uses an encryption software called &lt;a href="https://cryptomator.org/"&gt;Cryptomator&lt;/a&gt; that creates an encrypted folder in his Dropbox. The master password for this vault is a password he remembers concatenated with one generated by pressing the button on the Yubikey. Inside the vault is a file that contains passwords and recovery codes for other services as well as other sensitive files.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Where possible Chris also likes to use the Yubikey’s &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Universal_2nd_Factor"&gt;Universal 2nd Factor&lt;/a&gt; support to log in to online services. Google, Github, Dropbox and others support this standard.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="sliding-puzzles"&gt;Sliding Puzzles&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris then gave us a preview of a topic he’s going to talk about in more detail at the &lt;a href="http://lrug.org/meetings/2018/april/"&gt;April London Ruby User Group&lt;/a&gt; meeting: sliding puzzles.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tuzz/sliding_puzzle/master/frog.jpg" alt="A sliding puzzle featuring a frog. " /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris was inspired to play around with sliding puzzles after seeing one mentioned in one of Alan Turing’s papers during a visit to Bletchley Park. It turns out that Sliding Puzzles are used as a model problem in computer science due to their combinatorial complexity. For example, a 4x4 puzzle with one missing tile (a “Fifteen puzzle”) contains 16!/2 (around 10^13) states. Storing all of these states in memory would require a huge amount and therefore calculating the shortest path to a solution, for example, is a tough problem.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris talked us through some strategies for solving the puzzles efficiently including using invarients (ruling out some moves immediately due to their configuration), and pre-computing solutions to store in an “oracle”. Chris has also been learning Rust by applying it to this problem and has &lt;a href="https://github.com/tuzz/sliding_puzzle_rust"&gt;some code&lt;/a&gt; to pre-compute puzzles much faster than can be done in Ruby.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more - be sure to attend Chris’s LRUG talk.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="ethereum"&gt;Ethereum&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tom C showed us something he’s been working on with the &lt;a href="https://www.ethereum.org/"&gt;Ethereum&lt;/a&gt; platform. Starting with the observation that the maximum number of transactions that crypto-currencies like Bitcoin can handle is quite a lot less than what a modern credit-card system like Visa can handle, folks have been thinking of ways to speed things up.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/tom_show_and_tell.jpg" alt="Tom talking about Ethereum." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One approach is to perform transactions on a “side chain” and then periodically reconcile them with the main blockchain. Using such strategies opens up new avenues for bad actors to exploit, and Tom has been researching how these attacks might work and how best to prevent them. The theory uses mathematics derived from the study of games and how, for example, to decide who wins a game if one of the players decides to not complete their move.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="parsec"&gt;Parsec&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben rounded off the evening for us by giving a quick demo and explanation of &lt;a href="https://parsecgaming.com/"&gt;Parsec&lt;/a&gt;. Ben’s son really wanted to play a game that’s only available on Windows. There’s no Windows machines in Ben’s house so Ben first tried to create a virtual machine on Amazon’s AWS service to run the game. This worked OK, but suffered from some latency that made the game difficult to play. After some research they discovered Parsec which allows virtual gaming machines in the cloud to be efficiently streamed to a local machine. Ben’s really impressed with how easy it was to set up and the performance. And his son got his gaming fix!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;!-- add content here --&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-03-16:/week-478</id>
    <published>2018-03-16T12:23:42+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-16T12:23:42+00:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-478" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 478</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-roos</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-478"&gt;Week 478&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ve spent the week working from &lt;a href="http://space4.tech"&gt;Space4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.theofficegroup.co.uk/"&gt;TOG&lt;/a&gt; Bloomsbury and home.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pair_programming"&gt;paired&lt;/a&gt; more this week than we have for a while. It’s reminded me how much I enjoy it, and how effective it can be. Although we communicate regularly throughout the day, that’s still not quite the same as having two people working through a single problem.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="asset-manager"&gt;Asset Manager&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’re continuing to focus on the GDS &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/asset-manager"&gt;Asset Manager&lt;/a&gt; work. It feels as though we’re really not too far from being able to serve the &lt;a href="http://github.com/alphagov/whitehall"&gt;Whitehall&lt;/a&gt; attachments from Asset Manager (although it’s felt like that for a while).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ve been improving the Whitehall code by pulling apart some unwieldy logic into more expressive methods. This makes the code easier to understand and helps give us confidence that we’re correctly updating the assets in Asset Manager.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ve also been improving the Whitehall &lt;a href="http://sidekiq.org/"&gt;Sidekiq&lt;/a&gt; workers that communicate with Asset Manager. They’d grown somewhat organically and we’d ended up storing a fair amount of state on the queue. Not only can this state be out of date by the time the job is processed, but storing lots of data on the queue can eat into the memory available to &lt;a href="https://redis.io/"&gt;Redis&lt;/a&gt; (as we discovered in &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/week-473#gds"&gt;week 473&lt;/a&gt;!) The workers now take a single database ID which minimises the memory use and allows us to retrieve the state at job process time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ve added code and a Rake task in preparation for updating the metadata of all Whitehall attachments in Asset Manager. This is the final step before we can switch serving these assets from Asset Manager!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="gfr"&gt;GFR&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We received some more detailed feedback about why we were rejected for the coaching opportunity we mentioned in &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/week-475"&gt;week 475&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve not read through it in detail yet but hopefully it’ll help us understand what we can do to improve.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Cat and Annie of &lt;a href="http://www.thedotproject.co/"&gt;The Dot Project&lt;/a&gt; continue to do a great job of working with a subset of &lt;a href="https://www.coops.tech/"&gt;CoTech&lt;/a&gt; members to produce something that can be used to sell CoTech services to larger organisations.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; has archived some of our older repositories after we received vulnerability warnings from &lt;a href="https://www.github.com/"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, including the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/freerange/status/974023264682078208"&gt;fondly remembered Freerange Beards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ve accepted the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_Data_Protection_Regulation"&gt;GDPR&lt;/a&gt; variations to the &lt;a href="https://digitalmarketplace.blog.gov.uk/2015/12/07/digital-outcomes-and-specialists-is-open-for-applications/"&gt;Digital Outcomes and Specialists Framework&lt;/a&gt;. The more I read about GDPR the more impressed I am by its intent. I look forward to seeing the back of some of the more underhand practices that certain services employ.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Until next time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– Chris&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-03-14:/week-478-links</id>
    <published>2018-03-14T16:51:56+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-14T16:51:56+00:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-478-links" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 478 - Interesting links</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-roos</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-478---interesting-links"&gt;Week 478 - Interesting links&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;h3 id="git-triviahttpstwittercomtomstuartstatus973667727826149382"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomstuart/status/973667727826149382"&gt;Git trivia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://codon.com/"&gt;Tom S&lt;/a&gt; explains that, when splitting a commit during an interactive rebase, it’s possible to see the parts of the original change that are outstanding using the following command. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;JM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt; git diff `cat .git/rebase-merge/stopped-sha` &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="cotech-community-call-2httpsblogweareopencoopcotech-community-call-2-ce978934fc8f"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.weareopen.coop/cotech-community-call-2-ce978934fc8f"&gt;CoTech Community Call #2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I really appreciate &lt;a href="https://www.laurahilliger.com/"&gt;Laura Hilliger&lt;/a&gt; taking the time to write up these notes. GFR gets a bit of a mention. Thanks to &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-lowis"&gt;Chris L&lt;/a&gt; for being the voice of Go Free Range on the call! &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;JM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="lessons-learned-writing-data-pipelineshttpsmediumcomvictorariaslessons-learned-writing-data-pipelines-5746deb630a8"&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@victorarias/lessons-learned-writing-data-pipelines-5746deb630a8"&gt;Lessons learned writing data pipelines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Victor Arias talks about some of the hard-won lessons he learned building the data warehouse infrastructure at &lt;a href="https://futurelearn.com"&gt;FutureLearn&lt;/a&gt;. I also worked on this system and we often spoke about how we’d love to share what we were doing but never seemed to find the time. Victor has decided to try to post one thing a week with the barrier to publishing being &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ariassp/status/968623155366555648"&gt;something helpful that someone around him didn’t know about&lt;/a&gt;. I think that’s a really good strategy and look forward to reading more. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-lowis"&gt;CL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="what-the-jot-command-can-do-for-youhttpswwwnetworkworldcomarticle3200222linuxwhat-the-jot-command-can-do-for-youhtml"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.networkworld.com/article/3200222/linux/what-the-jot-command-can-do-for-you.html"&gt;What the jot command can do for you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I came across &lt;code&gt;jot&lt;/code&gt; when looking for a way of generating a random number within a range (between 1 and the total number of lines in a text file). I’d not come across it before but it worked perfectly for what I wanted to be able to do. The &lt;code&gt;jot&lt;/code&gt; utility does more than just generate random numbers and this article gives some examples of what it can be used for. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-roos"&gt;CR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="the-proposed-contract-variation-for-digital-outcomes-and-specialists-2httpswwwgovukgovernmentuploadssystemuploadsattachmentdatafile686085proposed-contract-variation-digital-outcomes-and-specialists-2pdf"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/686085/proposed-contract-variation-digital-outcomes-and-specialists-2.pdf"&gt;The proposed contract variation for Digital Outcomes and Specialists 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;We were recently asked to agree to GDPR-related changes in the contract for the Digital Outcomes and Specialists Framework. I was really happy to see that the changes were clearly displayed using a diff-like output: red and green highlighting to differentiate between removals and additions. We’ve received numerous contract variations in the past that require fairly significant work to see what’s actually changed so it’s great to see this approach by &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/digital-outcomes-and-specialists-2-framework-agreement"&gt;GDS/CSS&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-roos"&gt;CR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-03-08:/week-476</id>
    <published>2018-03-08T21:26:20+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-08T21:26:20+00:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-476" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 476</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-lowis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-476"&gt;Week 476&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris R spent Monday in Belfast on a short break for his birthday. Happy Birthday Chris! As the end of our current project approaches we poured most of our effort into trying to get the Asset Manager work into a state where we’d be happy to hand things over.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ve been facing a bit of a dilemma. For most of the last year on the two projects we’ve worked on for GDS, we’ve approached the development work in the same we always do. By trying to deliver small, incremental changes that add value to the system. We do this so that if circumstances change and we need to change direction, work on something different, or stop work altogether we are able to do so in the knowledge that we’re leaving the system we’re working on in a better state than we found it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;With the last part of the asset manager work - moving the remaining “attachment” assets from Whitehall to Asset Manager - we have struggled to find a way to break the problem into small pieces that can be delivered separately. We can’t find a way to start serving these assets from Asset Manager (and by proxy, Amazon’s S3 service) without migrating all of the assets, implementing the appropriate permissions system in Asset Manager, and adding functionality to ensure that when editors change the permissions of documents in Whitehall we make sure those changes are also reflected in Asset Manager. As a result, we need to do all of those things before we can finally switch over.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Whitehall is quite a complicated rails application and the more we work on these aspects the more small, unexpected issues we find. As an example, this week I worked on &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/whitehall/pull/3826"&gt;changing the CSV preview functionality&lt;/a&gt; (for example, &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/603201/Postcode_level_gas_estimates_2015_experimental.csv/preview"&gt;this preview&lt;/a&gt; of a dataset of domestic gas consumption estimates) so that it didn’t rely on reading the file from disk, as shortly we hope the files will no longer be on the disk at all. It was a small change that took quite a bit of time to get right.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’re worrying a little bit about the possibility of writing a lot of code that doesn’t ultimately allow us to fully switch the serving of these assets to Asset Manager and that this inconsistency might ultimately make it harder for future developers to understand the system than if we just revert back to a previous, more consistent state. We don’t want to have to do that, and we’ll be thinking of ways around it when we talk to GDS in Week 477.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the meantime Chris prepared and delivered a &lt;a href="https://github.com/freerange/gds-asset-manager-presentation"&gt;great, short overview&lt;/a&gt; of the changes we’d made to asset serving at a tech talk in the GDS Whitechapel office. There was a lot of useful discussion after the talk and we think it helped other developers to understand how things have changed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="other-good-things"&gt;Other good things&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Wednesday Chris and I spoke to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hazelsheffield"&gt;Hazel Sheffield&lt;/a&gt; who is writing an article about tech co-operatives and &lt;a href="https://www.coops.tech/"&gt;CoTech&lt;/a&gt;. We ended the week with our usual team meeting and retrospective - this time entirely remotely.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;!-- add content here --&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-03-02:/week-476-links</id>
    <published>2018-03-02T17:20:26+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-02T17:20:26+00:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-476-links" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 476 - Interesting links</title>
    <author>
      <name>james-mead</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-476---interesting-links"&gt;Week 476 - Interesting links&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;h3 id="discussing-cheese-and-a-bit-of-politics-with-jeremy-corbynhttpsoutlandishcombloggeneraldiscussing-cheese-with-jeremy-corbyn"&gt;&lt;a href="https://outlandish.com/blog/general/discussing-cheese-with-jeremy-corbyn/"&gt;Discussing cheese, and a bit of politics, with Jeremy Corbyn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;We were sorry to miss this event at &lt;a href="http://space4.tech/"&gt;Space4&lt;/a&gt; a couple of weeks back, but kudos to &lt;a href="http://outlandish.com/"&gt;Outlandish&lt;/a&gt; for getting Jeremy Corbyn’s attention and telling him all about &lt;a href="https://www.coops.tech"&gt;CoTech&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;JM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="using-technology-for-monitoring-evaluation-research-and-learninghttpswwwmeetupcomnetsquaredlondonevents248240303"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/netsquaredlondon/events/248240303/"&gt;Using technology for monitoring, evaluation, research, and learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is an event organised by &lt;a href="http://www.netsquared.org/"&gt;NetSquared&lt;/a&gt; London which is being held at &lt;a href="http://space4.tech/"&gt;Space4&lt;/a&gt; to help charities make the best use of technology. We’re sponsoring the food and drinks. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;JM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="reasons-why-i-love-working-at-our-not-for-profit-digital-co-ophttpsmediumcomdevsociety10-reasons-why-i-love-working-at-our-not-for-profit-digital-co-op-with-gifs-c4233206c0bc"&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@devsociety_/10-reasons-why-i-love-working-at-our-not-for-profit-digital-co-op-with-gifs-c4233206c0bc"&gt;10 reasons why I love working at our not-for-profit digital co-op&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;While we’re don’t operate exactly like our fellow &lt;a href="https://www.coops.tech"&gt;CoTech&lt;/a&gt; co-op, &lt;a href="https://www.dev.ngo/"&gt;The Developer Society&lt;/a&gt;, there are definitely a lot of similarities. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;JM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="are-you-a-senior-designerhttpsmediumcombenhollidayseniority-in-design-5169a39465c8"&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@BenHolliday/seniority-in-design-5169a39465c8"&gt;Are you a senior designer?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I came across this article via &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/beng/status/969129743151968256"&gt;a tweet from Ben G&lt;/a&gt;. Like Ben I think this applies just as much to all senior positions and, despite all my years of experience (yawn!), it reminded me that there are still some important things I’m not always very good at! &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;JM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="delphihttpswwwembarcaderocomproductsdelphi"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.embarcadero.com/products/delphi"&gt;Delphi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I have some relatively fond memories of developing software using Delphi back in the late nineties. I was extremely surprised to discover that it still exists! Via &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/headius/status/966831073350045698"&gt;a tweet from Charles Nutter&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;JM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="happy-birthday-webarchitectshttpswwwwebarchitectscoop20th"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.webarchitects.coop/20th"&gt;Happy Birthday Webarchitects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Our friends at Webarchitects are celebrating 20 years in operation as a co-operative. It’s really inspiring to see a tech co-op that’s been around for so long and we wish them all the very best for the future. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-lowis"&gt;CL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-02-23:/week-475</id>
    <published>2018-02-23T14:11:24+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-02-23T14:11:24+00:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-475" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 475</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-roos</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-475"&gt;Week 475&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ve worked from a number of &lt;a href="http://www.theofficegroup.co.uk/"&gt;TOG&lt;/a&gt; offices (including trying their Black &amp;amp; White building - it was quiet but not quite as comfortable as some of the others) and from home. &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-lowis"&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; took a day off on Wednesday for some travel and I’m off to Belfast today.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ve continued to focus on the &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/asset-manager"&gt;Asset Manager&lt;/a&gt; project as we enter the last couple of weeks of the project. Having got all of the &lt;a href="http://github.com/alphagov/whitehall"&gt;Whitehall&lt;/a&gt; attachments uploaded to Asset Manager, we’ve been concentrating on adding all the necessary functionality to Whitehall/Asset Manager to allow us to serve them: including storing/sending the size of assets in Asset Manager, allowing Asset Manager assets to be access limited and redirecting when an older asset is replaced. This is proving somewhat trickier than we’d hoped but we’re doing our best to get it done before we handover to a team at GDS. We had one of our final catch-ups with GDS on Tuesday and explained that it’s possible we’ll have to continue for an additional week past our contract end date (at cost to us, naturally).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We hosted our 41st &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-events"&gt;Show &amp;amp; Tell&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href="http://forgeandco.co.uk/"&gt;Forge &amp;amp; Co&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday. We had a good turnout, including a new attendee, and a good evening despite the cold conditions. As always, &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/contact"&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; if you’re interest in joining us at a future event.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I spent a while going through some code and documentation for a potential new project. It’s a bit out of our comfort zone but looks interesting and we’re hopeful we can get involved.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In slightly less positive news, we were rejected for another &lt;a href="https://digitalmarketplace.blog.gov.uk/2015/12/07/digital-outcomes-and-specialists-is-open-for-applications/"&gt;DO&amp;amp;S&lt;/a&gt; opportunity we applied for. It was a bit speculative as it was for some coaching (something we’ve not particularly done before) but it’s still a bit disappointing to hear that we didn’t meet their requirements.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And with that slight downer out of the way let’s finish on a high note.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris recently decided to bring his &lt;a href="http://www.webaudioweekly.com/"&gt;Web Audio Weekly&lt;/a&gt; newsletter into the GFR fold and we received the first payment for a job advert this week. Non-client-work revenue streams here we come!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; had a positive experience with an &lt;a href="https://github.com/freerange/mocha/issues/324"&gt;issue opened on Mocha&lt;/a&gt;: not only was the issue addressed by another user, but the original submitter took care of closing the issue they created. That’s the sort of open source interaction we like :-)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris did a great job in helping get the first &lt;a href="https://community.coops.tech/t/cotech-newsletter-february-2018/627/1"&gt;CoTech newsletter&lt;/a&gt; sent out today. This has been discussed within &lt;a href="https://www.coops.tech/"&gt;CoTech&lt;/a&gt; for quite some time so I was really pleased to see it in my inbox this morning.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I think that’s about all for this week. Until next time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– Chris&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
