<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>tag:x,2008-06-01:kind/x</id>
  <link href="http://localhost:3000" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <link href="http://localhost:3000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <title>Go Free Range Blog</title>
  <updated>2018-06-12T17:55:30+01:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-06-12:/week-488</id>
    <published>2018-06-12T17:55:30+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-12T17:55:30+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-488" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 488</title>
    <author>
      <name>james-mead</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-488"&gt;Week 488&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;Both Chrises were away all week, Chris R on paternity leave and Chris L on holiday in Portugal, leaving Ben and I to hold the fort. We spent the majority of the week continuing work on the project for &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/rd"&gt;BBC R&amp;amp;D&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben and I chose to do a lot of &lt;a href="http://www.extremeprogramming.org/rules/pair.html"&gt;pair programming&lt;/a&gt;, because we were working on an unfamiliar part of the codebase. During the week we did quite a bit of simplifying and refactoring - it’s easy to carried away with this kind of thing, but I think we did a good job of focussing on changes that would make it easier to add each piece of functionality.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We also spent quite a bit of time fixing warnings and generally improving the signal-to-noise ratio of the test output. This is a real bugbear of mine and development felt so much easier once it was done.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This was probably the most pair programming I’ve done in a while and the first time I’ve worked with Ben since the early/heady days of &lt;a href="https://www.reevoo.com/"&gt;Reevoo&lt;/a&gt; about 10 years ago! It reminded me how much I enjoy pair programming and I learnt loads from Ben during the week. Although at one point I think we both got a bit frustrated with an obscure problem configuring Ben’s editor to use &lt;a href="https://eslint.org/"&gt;ESLint&lt;/a&gt;, all in all I thoroughly enjoyed the experience!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Later in the week &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/robd"&gt;Rob D&lt;/a&gt; was in town and he spent a couple of days working in our office. He was doing a lot of &lt;em&gt;remote&lt;/em&gt; pair programming with a team of client developers, so it was interesting to hear about his experiences of that.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Anyway, that’s all for now. Until next time…&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– James&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-06-08:/week-490</id>
    <published>2018-06-08T17:51:51+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-08T17:51:51+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-490" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 490</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-roos</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-490"&gt;Week 490&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;Howdi, folks.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I spent the week easing back into work after the arrival of our first child in May. I mostly worked at home and kept busy with company admin and business development while &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/ben-griffiths"&gt;Ben&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-lowis"&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; finished up the work we were doing with the BBC.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="bbc-rd"&gt;BBC R&amp;amp;D&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We finished our work on BBC R&amp;amp;D’s &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/rd/projects/talking-with-machines"&gt;“Talking with Machines”&lt;/a&gt; project this week.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Monday and Tuesday were spent finishing up development in preparation for a final handover meeting on Wednesday. The BBC seemed really happy with the work we’ve done; remarking on how much we’ve achieved in such a short time. I don’t think we’re the best at recognising our achievements so it’s great to receive this sort of feedback.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We really enjoyed the project and are waiting for approval to write about it in more detail. In the meantime, if you’re interested to find out how we might help with your voice project please &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/contact"&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="internal-product-development"&gt;Internal product development&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ve resumed working on a product we were exploring before starting the BBC work. We think we’ve identified something that’s relatively common to product teams that we hope we can make simpler. We’ve distilled the idea to a core of what we believe to be useful and are now building something that we can use to test it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’re all excited by the idea and hope to have something to share soon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="cash-flow"&gt;Cash flow&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris and I started exploring improvements to our basic cashflow calculator. Our current calculator assumes that we keep aside money to cover all known liabilities (plus some contingency) irrespective of when they’re due. A combination of Ben joining, the new office and some delayed invoice payments means that we might have to “borrow” from our liability reserve. We want to improve the calculator to give us better visibility of what this means.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a href="https://www.freeagent.com/guides/cash-flow-forecast/"&gt;FreeAgent’s “How to make a cash flow forecast”&lt;/a&gt; particularly useful in understanding what we might need.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’re continuing to investigate.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="goodnight-disruption"&gt;Goodnight Disruption&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’re one of the sponsors of &lt;a href="https://www.coops.tech/"&gt;CoTech&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://londontechweek.com/event/goodnight-disruption-a-tech-week-party-by-cotech-innovation"&gt;Goodnight Disruption party&lt;/a&gt; during &lt;a href="https://londontechweek.com/"&gt;London Tech Week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://attending.io/events/goodnight-disruption"&gt;Sign up&lt;/a&gt; and come along to meet CoTech members and to learn more about the benefits of working with us.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;copy info="" from="" advert="" and="" suggest="" that="" people="" sign="" up=""&gt;. That's about all for now. Until next time. -- Chris &lt;/copy&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-06-08:/show-and-tell-44</id>
    <published>2018-06-08T11:32:05+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-08T11:32:05+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-44" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Show and Tell 44</title>
    <author>
      <name>james-mead</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="show-and-tell-44"&gt;Show and Tell 44&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;We decided to try holding this month’s event at our office in the Ministry of Startups in Whitechapel. We wondered whether holding the event a bit further away from the centre of London would discourage attendance, but seven people turned up, so perhaps we’ll do it again. We made do with a large monitor rather than the giant screen that we had access to at Forge &amp;amp; Co. This seemed to work OK, but it would be nice to have a bigger screen or a projector.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="migrating-web-apps-to-dokku"&gt;Migrating web apps to Dokku&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2018-06-07-show-and-tell-44-james-adam-dokku-demo.jpg" alt="James Adam demonstrating Dokku" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://lazyatom.com/"&gt;James A&lt;/a&gt; runs a bunch of web apps on his Linode VPS. They’re a pain to maintain, because each of them needs a different version of Ruby and several of them depend on specific packages like fonts &amp;amp; PhantomJS. Some time ago he hacked together a Docker pipeline which worked in a similar way to &lt;a href="https://github.com/tomafro/recap"&gt;Tom W’s &lt;code&gt;recap&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This built a Docker image locally, pushed it to a registry, and then pulled it down onto the VPS. This all worked OK, but was a bit of a pain and obviously relied on custom software to pull it all together.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Recently he decided to try moving all the apps to an installation of the open-source &lt;a href="https://www.heroku.com/"&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;-a-like &lt;a href="http://dokku.viewdocs.io/dokku/"&gt;Dokku&lt;/a&gt; on his VPS. He was pleasantly surprised how easy it was to do and particularly pleased that he was able to do it with zero downtime. He demonstrated how easy it is to use by creating a new Rails app and deploying it by pushing it to a git remote, just as you would for an app on Heroku. He explained that it uses &lt;a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/buildpacks"&gt;Heroku buildpacks&lt;/a&gt; and deploys the app to a &lt;a href="https://github.com/gliderlabs/herokuish"&gt;herokuish&lt;/a&gt; container.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Dokku provides zero-downtime deployments by default by managing an instance of Nginx outside Docker which is used to proxy request to the relevant container. When an app is deployed a new container is started alongside the existing one and once the new one is deemed healthy Dokku starts proxying new requests to the new container. James was able to run the Dokku-managed Nginx instance alongside the existing instance Apache on a different port and then swap over seamlessly once the relevant app was migrated.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="train-timetable-visualisation"&gt;Train timetable visualisation&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2018-06-07-show-and-tell-44-chris-zetter-marey-diagram-demo.jpg" alt="Chris Zetter demonstrating his train timetable visualisation tool" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://chriszetter.com/"&gt;Chris Z&lt;/a&gt; commutes by train between Hitchen and London. The recent &lt;a href="http://www.thameslinkprogramme.co.uk/canal-tunnels-open-new-north-south-london-connections-first-time"&gt;completion of the Canal Tunnels&lt;/a&gt; meant that trains could run from Finsbury Park to St Pancras for the first time. This resulted in a major change in the timetables from 20 May with his trains now routed through London via St Pancras rather than terminating at Kings Cross.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The train companies didn’t do a very good job of communicating the timetable changes (e.g. &lt;a href="https://www.railplan2020.com/-/media/goahead/railplan2020/may-timetables/tl-may-2018-thameslink-in-to--from-great-northern-mondays-to-fridays.pdf?la=en"&gt;a giant A3 PDF&lt;/a&gt;) and Chris was keen to see whether he could find a helpful way to visualise the changes. Initially he looked at fetching the data from the official &lt;a href="http://www.nationalrail.co.uk/100296.aspx"&gt;Darwin Data Feeds&lt;/a&gt;, but these are hard-to-use SOAP/XML feeds with strange acronyms. He then discovered he was able to obtain the relevant data from &lt;a href="https://www.transportapi.com/"&gt;transportapi&lt;/a&gt;’s more friendly JSON API under one of their free plans. He then used this data to generate &lt;a href="https://www.edwardtufte.com/bboard/q-and-a-fetch-msg?msg_id=0003zP#bboard_content"&gt;Marey-style diagrams&lt;/a&gt; with some custom code in conjunction with the &lt;a href="https://d3js.org/"&gt;D3.js&lt;/a&gt; charting library.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2018-06-07-show-and-tell-44-kings-cross-to-hitchin-marey-diagram.png" alt="Visualisation of changes to the train timetable from Kings Cross to Hitchen" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris has built &lt;a href="https://changes.chriszetter.com/"&gt;a general purpose tool&lt;/a&gt; which you can use to visualise the direct journeys between any two stations on the UK rail network. He’s also written the whole thing up in more detail &lt;a href="https://chriszetter.com/blog/2018/05/11/visualizing-changes-to-rail-services/"&gt;on his blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="programmatically-generated-maps"&gt;Programmatically generated maps&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p style="text-align: center"&gt; &lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2018-06-07-show-and-tell-44-animated-maps.gif" alt="Progression of maps for Alexa game" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In last month’s Show &amp;amp; Tell, we talked demonstrated the beginnings of a &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-43#writing-a-game-for-the-amazon-alexa"&gt;game for Amazon’s Alexa&lt;/a&gt;, in which the player starts in an unknown position on a map and has to navigate a ship to port by listening to the sounds around them as if they were lost in fog. This time Ben demonstrated how he had programmatically generated a realistic looking map from a simple ASCII grid.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben was inspired by &lt;a href="https://mewo2.com/notes/terrain/"&gt;Martin O’Leary’s maps&lt;/a&gt; which are published via &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/unchartedatlas"&gt;@unchartedatlas&lt;/a&gt;. The first stage of Ben’s approach was to plot a load of random points and to divide the plane into a polygon per point by finding all the points which are closer to the random point than any other. This division into polygons is called a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voronoi_diagram"&gt;Voroni diagram&lt;/a&gt; and Ben used the &lt;a href="https://github.com/abscondment/rubyvor"&gt;rubyvor&lt;/a&gt; library to implement this.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The next stage is to annotate various points on each polygon based on data from the underlying ASCII grid used by the game mechanics. For example, calculating a height based on distance from the coast plus/minus some randomness. The idea being to generate a physical representation of a somewhat realistic landscape. The final stage is to colour in the map based on this physical representation and doing some blending and blurring.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’m sorry the above isn’t a very fulsome explanation, but if you’re interested in knowing more, &lt;a href="https://github.com/freerange/we-didnt-mean-to-go-to-sea/blob/d450474e7f5b657fd3dd96c9c6361043eaa6c779/maps/mapgen.rb"&gt;the code is publicly accessible on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. I think the end result looks great and I hope we manage to find the time to do some more work on this game.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="celestial-navigation"&gt;Celestial navigation&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2018-06-07-show-and-tell-44-james-with-sextant.jpg" alt="James with sextant" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I had brought along the cheap plastic &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sextant"&gt;sextant&lt;/a&gt; that I own and showed people how to use it, although it wasn’t ideal because we couldn’t see either the sun or the horizon! I described a couple of the simpler ways you can determine both your latitude and longitude your using just a sextant, a nautical almanac and an accurate watch.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For example, taking a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Longitude_by_chronometer#Noon_sight_for_Longitude"&gt;noon sight&lt;/a&gt; where, if you know the approximate time of local noon, you measure the altitude of the &lt;a href="https://encyclopedia2.thefreedictionary.com/lower+limb"&gt;lower limb&lt;/a&gt; of the sun 15-30 minutes before local noon making a note of the exact time, then leave this altitude set on the sextant, and wait for the lower limb of the sun to drop back down to the same altitude after local noon, recording the exact time at which this happens. You can then average the two times to obtain a very accurate time for local noon which is easily converted into a longitude for your position at local noon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2018-06-07-show-and-tell-44-ben-using-sextant.jpg" alt="Ben using sextant" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I got in a bit of a muddle about how some of the maths worked, but hopefully people got the idea. I finished up by explaining how it’s possible to apply corrections to make the measurements as accurate as possible, e.g. correcting for error in the sextant itself (index error), adjusting for the height of your eye above the horizon, and correcting for refraction of light in the atmosphere, particularly important when celestial objects are low in the sky.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="show--tell-45"&gt;Show &amp;amp; Tell 45&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ll be hosting our 45th Show &amp;amp; Tell in June. Please &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/contact"&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; if you’d like to join us.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-05-18:/week-487</id>
    <published>2018-05-18T15:54:17+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-18T15:54:17+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-487" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 487</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-lowis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-487"&gt;Week 487&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hello folks!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some fantastic news arrived at the end of the week as &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-roos"&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; and his partner Amy welcomed their new baby into the world. We’re all really happy and excited here at Go Free Range. Congratulations!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This week we got the go-ahead to spend a couple more weeks working for BBC R&amp;amp;D on their &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/rd/projects/talking-with-machines"&gt;“talking with machines”&lt;/a&gt; project. In particular the team were happy with the new features we’d added to Orator (which is used to author voice experiences) and wanted us to continue refactoring and documenting it in order to make it easier for other teams to use and maintain. We’ve really enjoyed having some creative freedom to make these changes and it’s great to work with a client who gives us a problem to solve and is excited to learn more about how we’ve gone about solving it. It was great to have Sean and Ant from BBC R&amp;amp;D in our offices on Wednesday morning to work with them on the next steps.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the meantime we’ve continued talking to prospective clients and meeting with old friends to learn more about what they’re working on and where &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/upcoming-availability"&gt;we might be able to help&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We signed off our annual accounts after &lt;a href="http://www.goddardsolutions.co.uk/"&gt;Dawn&lt;/a&gt;, our accountant, sent us the final version. Dawn also helpfully prepared the accounts in two formats - &lt;a href="https://www.icaew.com/technical/financial-reporting/new-uk-gaap/frs-102-the-financial-reporting-standard"&gt;FRS102&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.icaew.com/en/technical/financial-reporting/new-uk-gaap/frs-105-the-financial-reporting-standard-applicable-to-micro-entities"&gt;FRS105&lt;/a&gt;. The former is the longer-form version of the accounts that we have submitted in previous years. The latter is a newer, abbreviated version designed to make filing easier for “micro” companies. We’ve decided to submit the longer version but seeing both versions side-by-side really helped us to understand the difference.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ve also asked Dawn to look into whether any of our work might qualify for &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/corporation-tax-research-and-development-rd-relief"&gt;R&amp;amp;D Tax Credit&lt;/a&gt; relief. We need to provide some more information about what we’ve been working on and how we tackle problems.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago we &lt;a href="https://community.coops.tech/t/cotech-at-london-tech-week/613/31"&gt;decided to pay for a listing&lt;/a&gt; in the London Tech Week programme to promote CoTech - the network of worker co-ops that Go Free Range belongs to. The &lt;a href="https://londontechweek.com/event/goodnight-disruption-a-tech-week-party-by-cotech-innovation"&gt;Goodnight Disruption&lt;/a&gt; event is now listed and we’re looking forward to meeting a lot of people at the party on the 15th June.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Wishing you a great weekend.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;!-- add content here --&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-05-14:/week-485</id>
    <published>2018-05-14T15:59:27+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-14T15:59:27+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-485" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 485</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-lowis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-485"&gt;Week 485&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There was quite a bit going on this week. I’ve noticed that with our own office and 4 people things feel a bit more active. I think that’s partly because we can have “two pairs” working on things at the same time - which means there’s plenty of conversation happening when we’re working on a client project. We’ve also been visiting potential clients too - we’ve typically sent two of us to meet them, which means two people continuing to work and make progress while they’re gone.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here’s a brief summary of some of the things we got up to:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;We continued work on the project for the BBC. You can &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/rd/projects/talking-with-machines"&gt;read more about the project theme&lt;/a&gt; on the BBC blog. Last week we made some changes to the way voice experiences can be created. This week we used those new features to develop some prototype applications. We’re not really able to talk about the work in too much detail at this stage, but we’ve enjoyed working with a combination of &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/lambda/features/"&gt;AWS Lambda&lt;/a&gt;, the Alexa platform, NodeJS and Ruby.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;We’ve started working with a few folks within &lt;a href="https://www.coops.tech/"&gt;CoTech&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://community.coops.tech/t/cotech-at-london-tech-week/613/11"&gt;organise and sponsor an event&lt;/a&gt; during &lt;a href="https://londontechweek.com/"&gt;London Tech Week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;We spoke to an NGO about taking on a small amount of maintenance work for their Rails application.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;We gave up our desks at the lovely &lt;a href="http://space4.tech/"&gt;Space4&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re looking for co-working space within a really positive environment, you should speak to Polly.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;We met a potential client in their offices to discuss some work. The meeting was positive.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;We had a brief chat with our new office neighbours &lt;a href="https://socialvalueexchange.org/"&gt;Social Value Exchange&lt;/a&gt; and suggested some ways they could find suitable developers to work with them.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Chris R helped Joaquim sort out an email sending issue with the &lt;a href="https://fund.coops.tech/"&gt;CoTech CoBudget installation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;We switched to using the recently-resurrected &lt;a href="https://upcoming.org"&gt;upcoming.org&lt;/a&gt; for our &lt;a href="https://upcoming.org/event/gfr-show-and-tell-44-0o3s38h967"&gt;Show and Tell&lt;/a&gt; event.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;!-- add content here --&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-05-09:/show-and-tell-39</id>
    <published>2018-05-09T13:11:26+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-09T13:11:26+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-39" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Show and Tell 39</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-roos</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="show-and-tell-39"&gt;Show and Tell 39&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://codon.com/"&gt;Tom S&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/beng"&gt;Ben G&lt;/a&gt; joined &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; and I for our 39th Show &amp;amp; Tell in Dec 2017.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="rspecs-verifying-doubles"&gt;RSpec’s Verifying Doubles&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2017-12-13-show-and-tell-39-tom-s.jpg" alt="Tom talking about Verifying Doubles" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tom explained how he updated the &lt;a href="https://www.futurelearn.com/"&gt;FutureLearn&lt;/a&gt; tests to use &lt;a href="http://rspec.info/blog/2014/05/notable-changes-in-rspec-3/#verifying-doubles"&gt;RSpec’s Verifying Doubles&lt;/a&gt; after a recent upgrade to RSpec 3. Verifying Doubles are similar to standard doubles but with the added benefit of verifying that the stubbed methods exist on the object they’re being stubbed on.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tom’s using the &lt;code&gt;instance_double('Foo')&lt;/code&gt; syntax (as opposed to &lt;code&gt;instance_double(Foo)&lt;/code&gt;) which toggles verification based on whether the &lt;code&gt;Foo&lt;/code&gt; constant is defined. This allows the tests to run quickly in isolation but with the added benefit of verification when run in the context of the application (i.e. when all the dependencies are loaded).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tom’s ended up disabling verification in their Rails view specs. There were a number of tests that he couldn’t get to work with double verification. He initially disabled verification for those tests (using &lt;a href="http://rspec.info/blog/2017/05/rspec-3-6-has-been-released/#mocks-withoutpartialdoubleverification"&gt;&lt;code&gt;without_partial_double_verification&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) but decided that the cost of having to think about when to disable it didn’t justify the benefit of having it enabled.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Shortly after merging the changes to master they caught a problem that would’ve otherwise probably made it to production. A column was renamed in a migration which broke some code making use of &lt;code&gt;find_by_&amp;lt;old_column_name&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. This &lt;code&gt;find_by&lt;/code&gt; method was being stubbed in a test which would’ve continued to pass had the double verification not complained about the unknown method.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The discussion reminded James M of &lt;a href="https://blog.magpiebrain.com/2004/07/27/oo-matron/"&gt;OO-Matron&lt;/a&gt; by Nat Pryce, although I’m afraid I no longer recall what the similarities were.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="teaching-3d"&gt;Teaching 3D&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2017-12-13-show-and-tell-39-ben-g.jpg" alt="Ben talking about 3D rendering" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben spoke about an alternative way of teaching people about 3D modelling. Unfortunately, because the event was 6 months ago and because of my lack of subject knowledge, my notes no longer make any sense to me and so I’m not going to be able to do this any justice. Sorry, Ben!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-05-01:/show-and-tell-38</id>
    <published>2018-05-01T09:07:18+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-05-01T09:07:18+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-38" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Show and Tell 38</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-roos</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="show-and-tell-38"&gt;Show and Tell 38&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; and I were joined by &lt;a href="http://chris.patuzzo.co.uk/"&gt;Chris P&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://chriszetter.com/"&gt;Chris Z&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/beng"&gt;Ben G&lt;/a&gt; for our 38th Show &amp;amp; Tell.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="wordpress-site-hack"&gt;WordPress site hack&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;I kicked off the evening by talking about my attempts at repairing a hacked WordPress site.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We discovered the hack when we noticed that the site was redirecting to a porn site. We spoke to the website host and they identified a number of suspect .php files that we promptly removed. We thought this was the end of it until we got some reports of it continuing to redirect to other websites. I couldn’t immediately replicate the problem and so wondered whether the redirects might’ve been cached by certain browsers. Further investigation revealed this not to be the case: I was able to replicate the problem by manually setting my user agent. I eventually found the culprit hidden in a number of .htaccess files that had been written to the WordPress installation. These .htaccess files contained redirect rules that only applied when certain conditions were met (including based on the user agent). Removing the suspect .htaccess files appears to fix the problem!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I also investigated some of the rogue php files that had been uploaded. They were obfuscated so I used Ruby to unobfuscate the code to try to understand what was happening. Ben’s best guess was that it was used as part of a DDOS attack. The php would make a request to another website with some element of randomness.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben mentioned the &lt;a href="https://security.dxw.com/"&gt;DXW Security&lt;/a&gt; site as a good resource for these sort of problems.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="openstreetmap"&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2017-11-08-show-and-tell-38-chris-z-openstreetmap.jpg" alt="Chris Zetter describing his recent contribution to OpenStreetMap" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris Z talked us through a recent contribution he made to OpenStreetMap.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He’d noticed a new bridge near King’s Cross - Somers Town Bridge - and thought it was a good opportunity to add it to the map. Adding the bridge itself was relatively straightforward but he ran into problems when he tried to add the various access restrictions that applied to the bridge (e.g. opening times and the fact that it was privately owned but included public access). He wanted to get this right as he didn’t want someone to attempt to use the bridge when it was closed overnight. Having wrapped his head around the various rules he needed to add he eventually realised that there wasn’t any routing software that made use of them anyway!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="kindle-reading-history"&gt;Kindle reading history&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2017-11-08-show-and-tell-38-ben-g-kindle-library.jpg" alt="Ben demonstrating how to extract data from the Kindle Cloud Reader" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben’s son reads lots of books on his Kindle and Ben wanted some way of visualising them. He set about investigating how to scrape the Kindle Cloud Reader to get the data about the books in his son’s library. This turned out to be unnecessary because the Kindle Cloud Reader stores its data in a SQL database stored in the browser. This meant that extracting the data was as easy as using Safari’s “copy table” functionality to generate a tab-separated file.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The next step is to try to find pictures of the spines of books. A number of places have pictures of the front and back covers but none seem to have the spines.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Although the database contains details of all books in the library, it only seems to include reading data (e.g. the page you’re up to) for the books you’ve read in the Kindle Cloud reader.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’ve often wanted a way to visualise my reading history so I’m interested to see whether Ben makes any progress with this.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="the-tuzz-automation-tool"&gt;The tuzz automation tool&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2017-11-08-show-and-tell-38-chris-p-zz-automation.jpg" alt="Chris P updating us on his zz automation tool" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris P gave us a bit of an update on his &lt;a href="https://github.com/tuzz/zz"&gt;tuzz automation tool&lt;/a&gt; he &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-36#machine-automation"&gt;demoed at Show and Tell 36&lt;/a&gt;. He’s continuing to work on the tool and is using it to provision his laptop(s).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris also highlighted the similarities with his &lt;a href="https://github.com/tuzz/fortress"&gt;fortress project&lt;/a&gt; that he uses to provision his Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="magic-eye"&gt;Magic eye&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2017-11-08-show-and-tell-38-chris-p-magic-eye.jpg" alt="Chris P explaining his magic eye solving software" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris P showed us some &lt;a href="https://github.com/tuzz/magic_eye"&gt;Magic Eye&lt;/a&gt; (autosterogram images) solving software that he’d written a few years ago.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I understand that Chris is interested in rewriting the software to make use of some newer techniques that he’s learned. This generated some discussion about transforming problems from one domain to another in order to more easily solve them although I’m afraid it all went somewhat over my head.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="hough-transform"&gt;Hough Transform&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2017-11-08-show-and-tell-38-ben-g-hough-transform.jpg" alt="Ben G explaining the Hough transform" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris’s Magic Eye demo and discussion reminded Ben of his &lt;a href="https://techbelly.github.io/writing/Hough-Transform/"&gt;Hough Transform blog post&lt;/a&gt; work that &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-27#ben-g---blog-posts-and-distractions"&gt;he explained in Show &amp;amp; Tell 27&lt;/a&gt;. As above I’m afraid this also went over my head so I suggest reading Ben’s blog post if you’re interested in learning more.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-04-27:/show-and-tell-41</id>
    <published>2018-04-27T17:25:35+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-27T17:25:35+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-41" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Show and Tell 41</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-roos</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="show-and-tell-41"&gt;Show and Tell 41&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;James M&lt;/a&gt; and I were joined by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/chrispatuzzo"&gt;Chris P&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://chriszetter.com/"&gt;Chris Z&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://lazyatom.com/"&gt;James A&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://codon.com/"&gt;Tom S&lt;/a&gt; and first time attendee, &lt;a href="https://www.howlinbash.com/"&gt;Bash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="line-us"&gt;Line-us&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2018-02-23-show-and-tell-41-tom-s-hilbert-curve.jpg" alt="Tom with a Hilbert Curve" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tom S showed us his little &lt;a href="http://line-us.com/"&gt;Line-us&lt;/a&gt; drawing robot that he recently received after backing the &lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/line-us/line-us-the-little-robot-drawing-arm"&gt;product Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He showed us how to use the Line-us drawing app to control the robot before explaining how he’s been reverse engineering it to allow him to control it programmatically.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tom used &lt;a href="http://www.dns-sd.org/"&gt;DNS Service Discovery&lt;/a&gt; (DNS-SD) to find the device listening on port 1337 and then used Wireshark to inspect the traffic to and from the robot. Inspecting the traffic revealed some kind of heartbeat message being sent once per second as well as other messages that more obviously control the movement of the robot. At some point Tom realised these commands were all part of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/G-code"&gt;G-code&lt;/a&gt;, although not before he’d spent a while manually working out what they were doing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tom’s used what he learnt to write a multithreaded Ruby client that allows him to regularly send the heartbeat as well as the other commands he needs to control the arm. He demonstrated this working by instructing the arm to draw a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hilbert_curve"&gt;Hilbert Curve&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’m not sure I can necessarily think of a reason to own a Line-us but I was nevertheless impressed by Tom’s reverse engineering skills that allow him to control it programmatically.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="multiplayer-crosswords"&gt;Multiplayer crosswords&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2018-02-23-show-and-tell-41-chris-z-crossword.jpg" alt="Chris Z demonstrating his multiplayer crossword" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris Z explained that he’s been doing quite a few crosswords recently. Particularly on the Guardian. He often asks his partner for help with some of the clues and wondered whether it’d be possible to build something to allow them both to play at the same time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He discovered that the data for the Guardian crosswords (including the answers!) is stored as JSON in the page. The image is created as an SVG and the whole thing is a React component.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris found the source in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/guardian/frontend"&gt;Guardian’s frontend repository on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and managed to get it running on Heroku. He’s modified the React app to use websockets to allow multiple people to use it at the same time. He demonstrated this by having a number of us answering clues at the same time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He’s keen to share the project more widely but’s concerned that he might be violating the Guardian’s terms of service.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="generating-random-data"&gt;Generating random data&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;I spoke about using &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-gb/guide/automator/welcome/mac"&gt;Automator&lt;/a&gt; to generate data to help with manual testing during our asset manager work at GDS. I’d often find myself using the admin interface to create objects in the system and wanted a way of generating names for the things I was creating.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I started by sequentially numbering the things I was creating (e.g. “thing-1”, “thing-2”, “thing-n”) but it soon becomes hard to remember which number I was up to. I moved on to using timestamps (e.g. “2018-04-24 113700”, “2018-04-24 113730”) which were a bit better because I didn’t have to remember anything but were still a bit problematic because they’re hard to distinguish when you have a number of them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the end, I used a combination of a timestamp and a random word from the words file on my Mac. This naming convention has the advantage of conveying when the thing was created and of having a unique name that makes it easy to recognise in the short term.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="parsing-emails"&gt;Parsing emails&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;James A explained the difficulty he’s having in trying to reliably parse emails for some mailing list software he’s been working on. It might sound as though it should be a solved problem but it seems that even hosted services (e.g. &lt;a href="https://www.mailgun.com/"&gt;Mailgun&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://mailchimp.com/"&gt;Mailchimp&lt;/a&gt;) do it slightly differently and therefore it’s not completely obvious that you’d use such a service instead of writing something to parse them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="spacemacs"&gt;Spacemacs&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2018-02-23-show-and-tell-41-james-a-magit.jpg" alt="James A describing Spacemacs and magit" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;James A gave us a bit of an intro to &lt;a href="http://spacemacs.org/"&gt;Spacemacs&lt;/a&gt;. He’s switched editors a few times over the years and this is the first time in a while that he’s had some enthusiasm for one of them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;James explained that the extensive documentation and easily discoverable commands make it very easy to get started with. And that if you can see the value in Vim but have struggled to use it effectively then you might want to give Spacemacs a try.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He demonstrated the &lt;a href="https://magit.vc/"&gt;magit&lt;/a&gt; git package that provides git integration in the editor and briefly showed us his custom command/script that allows him to run &lt;code&gt;rails test&lt;/code&gt; from within the editor.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="karaoke"&gt;Karaoke&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2018-02-23-show-and-tell-41-bash-karaoke.jpg" alt="Bash showing his karaoke app" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Bash showed us the React karaoke app he’s building. It’s similar in style to early versions of iTunes in that it allows you to filter by Era, Genre, Artist and Song to help find the music you’re interested in. I’m not really up on the current state of karaoke but if it’s still common practice to flick through a book of hundreds of songs then I can imagine this being much easier to use.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Bash is building the app to help him learn React and to, ultimately, help him get to better karaoke parties :-)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-04-27:/week-484</id>
    <published>2018-04-27T15:52:41+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-27T15:52:41+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-484" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 484</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-roos</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-484"&gt;Week 484&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; took an impromptu week off having seen the favourable weather forecast at the end of last week.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/ben-griffiths"&gt;Ben&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-lowis"&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; and I moved into a larger 6-person office at &lt;a href="http://www.ministryofstartups.com/"&gt;Ministry of Startups&lt;/a&gt; on Monday, and have spent the week working on a project for &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/rd"&gt;BBC R&amp;amp;D&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ve got some &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/upcoming-availability"&gt;availability in the near future&lt;/a&gt; so please &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/mailto:lets@gofreerange.com"&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; if you have a project you think we can work together on.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="bbc-rd"&gt;BBC R&amp;amp;D&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;BBC R&amp;amp;D have developed a story editor and engine that allows them to create voice controlled stories (e.g. &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/rd/blog/2017-09-voice-ui-inspection-chamber-audio-drama"&gt;The Inspection Chamber&lt;/a&gt;) to run on multiple devices. They’ve asked us to explore how these stories might use information from arbitrary external services in order to make them feel more dynamic, and to come up with some demos of how this might be used.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We spent a while familiarising ourselves with the code before getting our hands dirty with some changes. Fortunately this familiarisation didn’t take too long after we’ve spent the past couple of weeks exploring and playing with voice controlled devices.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The story editor already includes the ability to branch a story based on the result of executing some arbitrary JavaScript code. We started by overloading this to return the response from an HTTP request if the code to execute looks like a URL. This allowed us to get something working without having to make changes to both the editor and the engine, and it revealed that we needed to make the engine asynchronous so that we could wait for the response from the external service. Ben updated the engine to make it use &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Guide/Using_promises"&gt;Promises&lt;/a&gt; all the way through while Chris and I paired on deploying the engine to AWS and hooking it all up so that we could interact with a story using the &lt;a href="https://developer.amazon.com/docs/devconsole/about-the-developer-console.html"&gt;Alexa Developer console&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ve finished the week with a simple game of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coin_flipping"&gt;Heads or Tails&lt;/a&gt;, authored in the story editor and running on a version of the engine that we’ve deployed to Lambda. The game asks you to choose heads or tails, makes a request to a web service that randomly chooses heads or tails and then lets you know whether you’ve won. It’s &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; simple but it gives us a good foundation to build on in order to create some more interesting demos.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Until next time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– Chris&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-04-26:/upcoming-availability</id>
    <published>2018-04-26T11:53:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-26T11:53:00+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/upcoming-availability" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Upcoming availability</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-lowis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="upcoming-availability"&gt;Upcoming availability&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;We have some availability coming up. Here’s a few ways we might be able to help you:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;We’re a team of 4 &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com#people"&gt;experienced developers&lt;/a&gt;. We’re happy &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/projects#harmonia"&gt;building new applications from scratch&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/projects#smart-answers"&gt;refactoring legacy code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;We enjoy working with existing teams and particularly coaching new developers. You might want to &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/projects#futurelearn-mooc-platform"&gt;build a team around us&lt;/a&gt; while we help you to establish good development practices.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;We prefer to work in an agile way. We can show you how that works and work with you to adopt agile practices.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Give us a problem to solve - we love &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/projects"&gt;creative projects&lt;/a&gt; and prototyping.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Our favourite language is Ruby and we’re happy to work on Rails projects. We can also turn our hand to JavaScript and iOS development. We’ve worked on web applications, data-processing systems, 3D graphics, voice-controlled applications including the Alexa, video- and audio-processing tools, data science and more. We love a challenge.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you think we might be able to work together &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/mailto:lets@gofreerange.com"&gt;drop us a line&lt;/a&gt; and we’ll arrange to meet you for a cuppa.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
