<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>tag:x,2008-06-01:kind/x</id>
  <title>Go Free Range Blog</title>
  <updated>2017-07-19T09:54:27+01:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>show-and-tell-34</title>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2017-07-19:/show-and-tell-34</id>
    <updated>2017-07-19T09:54:27+01:00</updated>
    <published>2017-07-19T09:54:27+01:00</published>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-34" />
    <author>
      <name>chris-roos</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="show-and-tell-34"&gt;Show and Tell 34&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; and I were joined by &lt;a href="http://amyeee.com/"&gt;Amy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/beng"&gt;Ben G&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://chris.patuzzo.co.uk/"&gt;Chris P&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cassarani"&gt;Leo&lt;/a&gt; for our 34th Show &amp;amp; Tell.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="hookline"&gt;Hookline&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2017-07-12-show-and-tell-34-amy.jpg" alt="Amy demoing the a Hookline product at Show &amp;amp; Tell 34" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Amy started the evening by demoing a new &lt;a href="http://hookline.tv/"&gt;Hookline&lt;/a&gt; product they’ve been working on: an online shop allowing content creators (e.g. YouTubers) to purchase music from the Hookline library to accompany their videos.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;They’ve combined &lt;a href="https://wordpress.com/"&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://woocommerce.com/"&gt;WooCommerce&lt;/a&gt; and the Hookline music library app to build the shop which is very nearly ready to go. Amy used the opportunity to do some impromptu user-testing with Chris P and hopefully found the feedback and general discussion useful.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;They’re currently looking for people to help test the service so if you’re interested get in touch with Amy. See the tweet below for details.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Need music for YouTube/online? In exchange for free track download &amp;amp; licence, I&amp;#39;d like to remotely observe you using a new service. Ping me!&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Amy Wagner (@amyeee) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/amyeee/status/885451369154580481"&gt;July 13, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async="" src="http://gofreerange.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="toilet-occupancy"&gt;Toilet Occupancy&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2017-07-12-show-and-tell-34-ben-g.jpg" alt="Ben G showing the infrared sensors at Show &amp;amp; Tell 34" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben’s current place of work only has two toilets and they’re at opposite ends of the office. The frustration of arriving at an occupied toilet and having to walk to the other end of the office has lead Ben to investigate ways of indicating whether a toilet is vacant.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He’s splashed out just over £10 on a couple of wireless motion sensors and a USB SDR device from eBay and has started to investigate how he might use them. The motion sensors broadcast data on a frequency of about 433Mhz and Ben’s using &lt;a href="http://cubicsdr.com/"&gt;CubicSDR&lt;/a&gt; to “see” the data that’s being broadcast. He’s hoping that the sensors contain and broadcast some kind of identifier so that he’s able to differentiate between them and indicate whether a toilet is vacant.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It sounds as though this isn’t a problem exclusive to Ben’s office as someone mentioned that &lt;a href="https://madebymany.com/stories/is-the-toilet-free."&gt;Made by Many have also written about solving this problem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="flag-poles-and-x-wing-fighters"&gt;Flag poles and X-Wing fighters&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben quickly showed us a couple of other smaller things he’s been working on recently.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He was particularly proud of discovering &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turnbuckle"&gt;Turnbuckles&lt;/a&gt; and how they could be used to erect a pirate flag in the garden.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Made a pirate flagpole for the pirate part of the garden. &lt;a href="https://t.co/PPVq4zNLCT"&gt;pic.twitter.com/PPVq4zNLCT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ben Griffiths (@beng) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/beng/status/879006061348487168"&gt;June 25, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async="" src="http://gofreerange.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;p&gt;He’s used ball bearings to fix and improve broken static X-Wing mounts with something that allows the fighters to bank in formation :-)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Thanks to Dremel and Superglue, replace broken x-wing mount with awesome nd magnet and ball-bearing. &lt;a href="https://t.co/JfvqpZvIJw"&gt;pic.twitter.com/JfvqpZvIJw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ben Griffiths (@beng) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/beng/status/868821621552930816"&gt;May 28, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async="" src="http://gofreerange.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="reliving-gps-tracks"&gt;Reliving GPS tracks&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;I spent two minutes demoing the &lt;a href="https://www.relive.cc/"&gt;Relive&lt;/a&gt; service/app. Connect it to your Garmin, Strava, Endomondo or Polar accounts and wait for it to generate a video showing a flyby of your route. If you run or cycle and use any of the supported accounts then I highly recommend trying it out.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="engine-electronics"&gt;Engine Electronics&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2017-07-12-show-and-tell-34-chris-r.jpg" alt="Chris R showing the simple dashboard for his boat" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I spent a couple of minutes explaining how I’d wired the starter motor and glow plugs of my boat engine to a simple wooden dashboard.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The work had been a bit of a eye-opener as I’d never really considered what happens when you turn the key in the ignition of a car. Wiring up a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; simple version in a boat has made it feel much less magic!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="simple-api-with-aws-lambda"&gt;Simple API with AWS Lambda&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;While we predominantly rely on &lt;a href="https://harmonia.io"&gt;Harmonia&lt;/a&gt; to distribute tasks between us we occasionally need to assign responsibility manually. I tend to use a snippet of Ruby similar to &lt;code&gt;%w(cl cr jm).shuffle.first&lt;/code&gt; to find an assignee and assume that Chris and James use something similar. Ideally I think we’d use some shared code to do this and I used that as an excuse to play with &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/lambda/"&gt;AWS Lambda&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I walked through the creation of a Lambda function and &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/api-gateway/"&gt;API Gateway&lt;/a&gt; to encapsulate a JavaScript version of the Ruby code above. The API Gateway allowed me to execute the function by making a HTTP request to the URL it gave me. I was pleasantly surprised by how relatively easy it was to connect it all together.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben mentioned &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/codestar/"&gt;AWS CodeStar&lt;/a&gt; which does everything I did but also gives you a git repository that you can push code to in order to deploy. This sounds great as it addresses one of the concerns I had about lack of commit history when editing code directly in the AWS Lambda interface.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="vpn"&gt;VPN&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2017-07-12-show-and-tell-34-james-m.jpg" alt="James M explaining his VPN set-up at Show &amp;amp; Tell 34" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;James explained how relatively cheap and easy it was to get his own VPN set-up. He rents a cheap server from &lt;a href="https://www.liteserver.nl/"&gt;LiteServer&lt;/a&gt; and has installed OpenVPN using &lt;a href="https://github.com/kylemanna/docker-openvpn"&gt;docker-openvpn&lt;/a&gt; and the related &lt;a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-run-openvpn-in-a-docker-container-on-ubuntu-14-04"&gt;tutorial from Digital Ocean&lt;/a&gt;. He connects using the open source &lt;a href="https://tunnelblick.net/"&gt;Tunnelblick&lt;/a&gt; client on his Mac.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;James thanks &lt;a href="http://po-ru.com"&gt;Paul B&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://lazyatom.com/"&gt;James A&lt;/a&gt; for their help and inspiration in getting this set-up.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="jekyll-guis"&gt;Jekyll GUIs&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;James gave us a quick demo of &lt;a href="https://www.siteleaf.com/"&gt;Siteleaf&lt;/a&gt;: a CMS for static sites. He discovered it as part of our investigation into switching the CoTech website from WordPress to Jekyll as one of the main arguments against Jekyll was the lack of user-friendly editing interface.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It was somewhat reassuring to hear Leo say that the marketing department at &lt;a href="https://www.geckoboard.com/"&gt;Geckoboard&lt;/a&gt; have been happily using Siteleaf for quite some time to administer their website.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben highlighted &lt;a href="https://security.dxw.com"&gt;dxwsecurity&lt;/a&gt; as a useful resource for people hosting WordPress. It sounds as though DXW have people working full time on assessing various security vulnerabilities in WordPress!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="magic-squares"&gt;Magic Squares&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2017-07-12-show-and-tell-34-chris-p.jpg" alt="Chris P explaining Magic Squares at Show &amp;amp; Tell 34" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris P introduced us to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magic_square"&gt;Magic Squares&lt;/a&gt;: square grids of numbers where each row, column and diagonal adds up to the same number (the magic sum).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Square with a magic sum of 21 ------------- | 8 | 9 | 4 | |----|---|----| | 3 | 7 | 11 | |----|---|----| | 10 | 5 | 6 | ------------- &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris went on to explain that there’s such a thing as an &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alphamagic_square"&gt;Alphamagic Square&lt;/a&gt;. These are special because replacing the number in each square with the number of letters in the English spelling of that number creates a new Magic Square! This is probably more easily understood with an example:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Square with a magic sum of 45 -------------- | 18 | 22 | 5 | |----|----|----| | 2 | 15 | 28 | |----|----|----| | 25 | 8 | 12 | -------------- Replace the numbers with their English names -------------------------------------- | eighteen | twentytwo | five | |------------|-----------|-------------| | two | fifteen | twentyeight | |------------|-----------|-------------| | twentyfive | eight | twelve | -------------------------------------- Replace the English names with number of letters and we get a square with a magic sum of 21 ------------- | 8 | 9 | 4 | |----|---|----| | 3 | 7 | 11 | |----|---|----| | 10 | 5 | 6 | ------------- &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris used &lt;a href="http://sentient-lang.org/"&gt;Sentient&lt;/a&gt;, his experimental programming language, to &lt;a href="https://github.com/tuzz/letterwise_magic_squares"&gt;discover a number of doubly Alphamagic squares&lt;/a&gt;! This has earned him a &lt;a href="https://www.futilitycloset.com/2017/05/07/double-alphamagic-squares/"&gt;write-up on Futility Closet&lt;/a&gt; and a mention on the Alphamagic Squares Wikipedia page.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris has also been searching for Alphamagic squares in other languages. He’s already found a number of Alphamagic squares in French but has so far hit the limits of his software when trying to find doubly Alphamagic ones.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="geckoboard-remote-control"&gt;Geckoboard remote control&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2017-07-12-show-and-tell-34-leo.jpg" alt="Leo demoing the Geckboard mobile &amp;quot;remote&amp;quot; at Show &amp;amp; Tell 34" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Leo demoed a prototype that he and three others built during a recent hack week at Geckoboard.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Leo and the team decided to try to improve the experience of managing Geckoboard &lt;a href="https://www.geckoboard.com/learn/guides/displaying-your-dashboard-on-a-screen/"&gt;dashboards that are being displayed on a big screen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;They ended up with a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Progressive_web_app"&gt;Progressive Web App&lt;/a&gt; that allows you to use your mobile as a remote to control the dashboards on a TV. You swipe horizontally through the dashboards available on your phone and flick them up toward the TV to select them (a nod toward something seen on &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/House_of_Cards_(U.S._TV_series)"&gt;House of Cards&lt;/a&gt;). Leo was demoing on an iPhone but explained that the experience on an Android is even better. Either way, it looked pretty slick from where I was sitting.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;They initially tried to use &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebRTC"&gt;WebRTC&lt;/a&gt; to link the phone and the big screen but had to give up when it became clear that it was going to take too long (they only had a week). They ended up using &lt;a href="https://pusher.com/"&gt;Pusher&lt;/a&gt; which seems to work really well despite initial concerns about lag.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="show--tell-35"&gt;Show &amp;amp; Tell 35&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’re hosting our 35th Show &amp;amp; Tell on Wednesday 9th August. It’s open to all so please &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/contact"&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; if you’d like to join us.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>week-443</title>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2017-07-14:/week-443</id>
    <updated>2017-07-14T14:59:45+01:00</updated>
    <published>2017-07-14T14:59:45+01:00</published>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-443" />
    <author>
      <name>chris-lowis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-443"&gt;Week 443&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hello! I’ve been working from home for most of this week. We had some family staying to help with our new arrival for the first few weeks of his life, but now they’ve gone home we’ve been on our own. It’s been great to spend time together but it’s taken until yesterday until I’ve felt that I’ve settled into a working routine.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Working remotely has also reminded me how much I enjoy the company of my colleagues - a few minutes spent with James at &lt;a href="https://www.theofficegroup.co.uk/office/east-side/"&gt;TOG East Side&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday afternoon made Thursday a whole lot more productive, for example. I’ve been experimenting with keeping much more granular lists of the work I need to do when programming. When I am able to concentrate for long spells I can usually keep it in my head, but writing it all down seems to make it much easier to cope with interruptions&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/#fn:1" class="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris and James met up on Tuesday and Wednesday and hosted a very enjoyable &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-events"&gt;Show and Tell event&lt;/a&gt; over at &lt;a href="http://forgeandco.co.uk/"&gt;Forge and Co&lt;/a&gt; in Shoreditch on Wednesday night.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Our work to migrate assets on &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/"&gt;GOV.UK&lt;/a&gt; to a cloud-based storage system continues. There are currently two systems that manage uploaded assets (images, PDF documents etc.) for GOV.UK. The &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/asset-manager"&gt;Asset Manager API&lt;/a&gt; provides a service that a variety of publishing applications integrate with, while the large publishing application &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/whitehall"&gt;Whitehall&lt;/a&gt; has its own asset management functionality. Both systems use the &lt;a href="https://github.com/carrierwaveuploader/carrierwave"&gt;Carrierwave&lt;/a&gt; library to store files on disk - with storage managed using an &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_File_System"&gt;NFS mount&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This week we’ve been working on &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/asset-manager/pull/63"&gt;adding support for Amazon’s S3 file storage&lt;/a&gt; to the Asset Manager API. As a first step we will upload the assets to &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/s3/"&gt;S3&lt;/a&gt; in parallel with the existing storage. This means we can work out any issues with integration without affecting the existing service. The configuration of AWS services used by GOV.UK is &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/govuk-terraform-provisioning"&gt;managed using Terraform&lt;/a&gt; so we’ve been getting to grips with how that works so we can add the S3 buckets and permissions that the Asset Manager API will need. Along the way we’ve been tidying up and updating the Asset Manager code, including &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/asset-manager/pull/66"&gt;making sure the code follows the GOV.UK linting rules&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For the Whitehall application we have two options. Either we migrate the storage for this application from NFS to S3 directly, and then look to remove the duplication between this application and the Asset Manager API. Or, we convert Whitehall to use the Asset Manager API first even if that requires us adding some features to the API that Whitehall needs. We’ve been spiking the latter approach to get a feel for how much work it will be.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As we mentioned last week, we’ve also been helping the Smart Answers team to make some changes to how the “start” pages are rendered. Chris &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/smart-answers/pull/3126"&gt;finished up the work on this&lt;/a&gt; and with the help of the team got it merged.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;!-- add content here --&gt; &lt;div class="footnotes"&gt; &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li id="fn:1"&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’ve been using the &lt;a href="http://orgmode.org/manual/Checkboxes.html"&gt;checkboxes feature&lt;/a&gt; in emacs &lt;a href="http://orgmode.org/"&gt;org mode&lt;/a&gt; for lightweight todo lists.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>week-441</title>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2017-07-11:/week-441</id>
    <updated>2017-07-11T13:37:33+01:00</updated>
    <published>2017-07-11T13:37:33+01:00</published>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-441" />
    <author>
      <name>chris-roos</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-441"&gt;Week 441&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;Having returned from an unsuccessful attempt at the &lt;a href="http://www.montblancmarathon.net/en/home"&gt;Mont Blanc 80km&lt;/a&gt; (I missed the cut-off at about the half way mark) I was away again on Monday to move our houseboat to the boat yard.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; returned from his break in the Isle of Wight on Tuesday and then took the later part of the week to sort a few things at home.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-lowis"&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; for holding the fort while James and I were away.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="cotech"&gt;CoTech&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Prompted by a discussion about the complexity of developing the existing &lt;a href="https://www.coops.tech/"&gt;CoTech&lt;/a&gt; website, James and I spent some time spiking on an implementation in &lt;a href="https://jekyllrb.com/"&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. We’re confident we can do everything required of the current site and &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; that such a migration will leave us with a simpler system. We started drafting a document to use as the basis of a proposal in &lt;a href="https://www.loomio.org/"&gt;Loomio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="asset-manager"&gt;Asset Manager&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;I joined Chris in getting stuck into the Asset Manager work for GDS. We started by digging into the problems we’re trying to solve in order to help us prioritise our work. Feedback from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/danielroseman"&gt;Daniel Roseman&lt;/a&gt; helped us formulate a bit of a bit of a plan of action. Chris started to investigate how we might use &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/s3/"&gt;S3&lt;/a&gt; to store assets.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="smart-answers"&gt;Smart Answers&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;I spent Friday reviewing a pull request in &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/smart-answers"&gt;Smart Answers&lt;/a&gt;. The idea is to split the introduction to the Smart Answer (the page that contains the “Start” button) from the actual content of the Smart Answer. Familiarity with the &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/publishing-api"&gt;Publishing API&lt;/a&gt; (due to our work with &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/manuals-publisher"&gt;Manuals Publisher&lt;/a&gt;) and with Smart Answers means that I hope I can provide some useful feedback about this change. Ideally I’ll pair with the developers involved as I think that’s going to be more effective (and easier) than trying to communicate asynchronously via comments.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="becoming-a-coop"&gt;Becoming a coop&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris finished converting the &lt;a href="https://www.uk.coop/developing-co-ops/model-governing-documents"&gt;Model governing document&lt;/a&gt; for a &lt;a href="https://www.uk.coop/developing-co-ops/model-governing-documents/worker-co-operative-company-limited-shares"&gt;Worker Co-operative Company Limited by Shares&lt;/a&gt; from a PDF to HTML and has &lt;a href="https://github.com/freerange/coop-model-documents"&gt;made them available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. The hope is that we can track the changes we make to the model document if we decide to adopt them ourselves.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="social"&gt;Social&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We met the ever energetic &lt;a href="http://www.thattommyhall.com/"&gt;Tom Hall&lt;/a&gt; for a drink on Tuesday. We had a good evening chatting about work, coops and CoTech.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;James and I hosted our monthly drinks at the &lt;a href="http://www.templebrewhouse.com/"&gt;Temple Brew House&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday. It wasn’t too busy and they had a huge selection of delicious beers. We were even joined by GFR alumnus &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomafro"&gt;Tom W&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That’s all for now. Until next time, folks.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– Chris&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>week-442</title>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2017-07-10:/week-442</id>
    <updated>2017-07-10T12:42:19+01:00</updated>
    <published>2017-07-10T12:42:19+01:00</published>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-442" />
    <author>
      <name>james-mead</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-442"&gt;Week 442&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;I felt this week was a bit fragmented and we struggled a bit to find our focus. For various reasons all three of us only met up to work together on Friday, although on three other days two of us did manage to meet up for at least half a day, mostly at &lt;a href="https://www.theofficegroup.co.uk/office/east-side/"&gt;TOG East Side&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Earlier in the week Chris R did &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/smart-answers/pull/3126"&gt;some good work&lt;/a&gt; helping some GDS developers export &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/smart-answers"&gt;Smart Answers&lt;/a&gt; “start” pages into the &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/content-store"&gt;Content Store&lt;/a&gt; so they and other “start” pages can be rendered consistently across &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/"&gt;GOV.UK&lt;/a&gt;. He visited the new &lt;a href="http://thewhitechapelbuilding.london/building.html"&gt;GDS office in Whitechapel&lt;/a&gt; to discuss this face-to-face with the relevant people.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At various points during the week, we all got a bit sucked into a &lt;a href="https://www.loomio.org/d/FnHRkxCO"&gt;lengthy discussion&lt;/a&gt; about switching the &lt;a href="https://coops.tech"&gt;CoTech website&lt;/a&gt; from Wordpress to a static generator like Jekyll. I’m not sure we managed to completely explain the advantages of making this change, but I do think a number of important issues have been raised, in particular how to best collaborate online. To this end we’re even more keen to help people within the CoTech network learn how to use tools like &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; and Github and hope to organise some skill-sharing sessions in the months ahead.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Wednesday we were all working from home and started the day with a useful video/audio catch-up using &lt;a href="https://appear.in"&gt;appear.in&lt;/a&gt;. Although for the first time we had a couple of niggles getting started, in general I’m finding this a better option than Skype or Google Hangouts. In particular I haven’t noticed the usual gradual degradation in audio as the call goes on.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Thursday morning, Chris L &amp;amp; I met up at the &lt;a href="https://departmentofcoffee.com/"&gt;Ministry of Coffee &amp;amp; Social Affairs&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href="https://www.theofficegroup.co.uk/office/133-whitechapel-high-street/"&gt;TOG Whitechapel&lt;/a&gt; foyer. I finished up some tweaking of the documentation Chris had written explaining where we’ve got to with the refactoring of &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/manuals-publisher/"&gt;Manuals Publisher&lt;/a&gt; and added a &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/manuals-publisher/blob/657a1f2084482662230643445af42813ac1be30a/docs/history.md"&gt;potted history of the project&lt;/a&gt; to put it in context. We’re pretty happy with &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/manuals-publisher/blob/657a1f2084482662230643445af42813ac1be30a/README.md#documentation"&gt;the end result&lt;/a&gt;. Chris continued his spike into switching the &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/asset-manager/"&gt;Asset Manager&lt;/a&gt; to use &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/s3/"&gt;AWS Simple Storage Service&lt;/a&gt; (S3).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After lunch we met up with Daniel Roseman, Tim Blair &amp;amp; Paul Bowsher to discuss where we’ve got to with Manuals Publisher and what our plans are for the work on asset management across GOV.UK. They seemed very happy with our Manuals Publisher documentation - Paul said he’s going to hold it up as an example to follow.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Regarding asset management, we agreed that our main priorities should be firstly to move assets off NFS onto S3 and secondly to reduce code duplication across Asset Manager &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/whitehall/"&gt;Whitehall&lt;/a&gt; apps. They also introduced us to Steve Harker, the Technical Architect responsible for GOV.UK infrastructure, who explained how our work fitted in to their wider plans.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Friday we mostly worked on GFR stuff. After a pleasant lunchtime discussion in the sun on a slightly damp patch of grass in &lt;a href="https://www.kingscross.co.uk/pancras-square"&gt;Pancras Square&lt;/a&gt;, we agreed a way to &lt;a href="https://www.loomio.org/d/FnHRkxCO/comment/1409145"&gt;draw a line under&lt;/a&gt; the discussion about the CoTech website mentioned above. Chris R then started trying to make some of the changes to the CoTech website which had precipitated our proposal in the first place.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We ended the day with a couple of drinks in the sun next to the canal outside &lt;a href="http://thelighterman.co.uk/"&gt;The Lighterman&lt;/a&gt; where we held our weekly retrospective.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That’s all folks!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– James&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>week-442-links</title>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2017-07-07:/week-442-links</id>
    <updated>2017-07-07T15:26:46+01:00</updated>
    <published>2017-07-07T15:26:46+01:00</published>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-442-links" />
    <author>
      <name>james-mead</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-442---interesting-links"&gt;Week 442 - Interesting links&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;h3 id="open-api-standards-for-uk-bankinghttpswwwopenbankingorguk"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openbanking.org.uk/"&gt;Open API Standards for UK Banking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I was interested to read of the release of v1.0.0 of &lt;a href="https://www.openbanking.org.uk/read-write-apis/"&gt;Open Banking Read/Write API specifications&lt;/a&gt;. I assume this is the result of the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/cma-paves-the-way-for-open-banking-revolution"&gt;Competition &amp;amp; Markets Authority’s report into retail banking&lt;/a&gt;. At first glance this looks promising, although it’s not obvious how soon we’re going to see any implementations. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;JM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="refactoring---not-on-the-backloghttpronjeffriescomxprogarticlesrefactoring-not-on-the-backlog"&gt;&lt;a href="http://ronjeffries.com/xprog/articles/refactoring-not-on-the-backlog/"&gt;Refactoring - Not on the backlog!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I think this old article contains a good explanation of why it’s better to embed refactoring into your day-to-day development, rather than rely on scheduling time explicitly for refactoring. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;JM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="child-benefit-tax-calculator-is-missing-pre-tax-pension-contribution-fieldhttpsgithubcomalphagovcalculatorspull173"&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/calculators/pull/173"&gt;Child benefit tax calculator is missing pre-tax pension contribution field&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I was fascinated to see this pull request by &lt;a href="http://dracos.co.uk/"&gt;Matthew Somerville&lt;/a&gt; in which he highlights some confusion in the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/child-benefit-tax-calculator"&gt;Child benefit tax calculator on GOV.UK&lt;/a&gt;. On the one hand, it’s great that the source code is open allowing Matthew to read the code to understand the calculations; on the other hand, it’s a real shame that he can’t interact more directly with the subject matter expert in the relevant department. Matthew also legitimately suggests that GOV.UK do some user testing on this application. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;JM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="why-large-technology-programmes-fail-and-what-to-do-insteadhttpsmediumcomdaverogwhy-large-technology-programmes-fail-and-what-to-do-instead-5bf8acce09ca"&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@daverog/why-large-technology-programmes-fail-and-what-to-do-instead-5bf8acce09ca"&gt;Why large technology programmes fail and what to do instead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Dave Rogers and Arif Harbott discuss some of the reasons why large technology projects fail to deliver - particularly in the context of the public sector. The sustained delivery capability the authors advocate is based on an alternative way of running public sector technology projects pioneered at places like our current client GDS and the Ministry of Justice where Dave is the CTO. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-lowis"&gt;CL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="cooling-the-tube--engineering-heat-out-of-the-undergroundhttpswwwianvisitscoukblog20170610cooling-the-tube-engineering-heat-out-of-the-underground"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ianvisits.co.uk/blog/2017/06/10/cooling-the-tube-engineering-heat-out-of-the-underground/"&gt;Cooling the tube – Engineering heat out of the Underground&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is a brilliantly detailed look at why it’s so hard to keep the London Underground cool and how the problems might be solved. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;JM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="ticketcleverhttpswwwticketclevercom"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ticketclever.com/"&gt;ticketclever&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;A new train journey planning website helping make sense of the ridiculously complicated UK rail network ticket pricing. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;JM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="introduction-to-parser-combinatorshttpsblogjcoglancom20170706introduction-to-parser-combinators"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jcoglan.com/2017/07/06/introduction-to-parser-combinators/"&gt;Introduction to parser combinators&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;James Coglan has prepared this article to as pre-reading for next week’s &lt;a href="http://london.computation.club/"&gt;London Computation Club&lt;/a&gt; meeting on parsers. It’s a fantastic overview of how to build increasingly capable systems by combining simple functional pieces. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-lowis"&gt;CL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="how-to-create-a-mooc-in-28-dayshttpswwwindiehackerscomsknthlahow-to-create-a-mooc-in-28-days"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.indiehackers.com/@sknthla/how-to-create-a-mooc-in-28-days"&gt;How to Create a MOOC in 28 Days&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ve occasionally talked about writing on-line courses to generate an alternative revenue stream, so I was interested to read this article about creating a MOOC on the &lt;a href="https://teachable.com/"&gt;teachable platform&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;JM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="monzos-2017-annual-reporthttpsmonzocomannual-report2017"&gt;&lt;a href="https://monzo.com/annual-report/2017/"&gt;Monzo’s 2017 Annual Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I really appreciate that &lt;a href="https://monzo.com/transparency/"&gt;Monzo’s transparency&lt;/a&gt; allows them to be so open with their annual accounts and reports. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-roos"&gt;CR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>week-440</title>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2017-06-23:/week-440</id>
    <updated>2017-06-23T13:09:38+01:00</updated>
    <published>2017-06-23T13:09:38+01:00</published>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-440" />
    <author>
      <name>chris-lowis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-440"&gt;Week 440&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;We spent the first two days of this week based out of our usual co-working space near the British Museum. On Wednesday James took a few days off to visit the Isle of Wight while Chris R headed to France for the &lt;a href="http://www.montblancmarathon.net/en/home"&gt;Mont-Blanc 80k&lt;/a&gt; run. I held the fort for the second half of the week.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Working in the way we do allows us to have some flexibility in where and when we work and with a newly-arrived baby it has been interesting to experiment with working patterns that work well for me and my family. I spent a couple of hours in the local library - they’ve recently refurbished and, in order to cut costs, switched to an automated system for door entry. It was good to spend time in the library training room and to take advantage of the free, if somewhat restricted&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/#fn:1" class="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, WiFi provided by Camden Council.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Tuesday the three of us went in to Aviation House to catch up with Daniel about our progress on Manuals Publisher and to learn more about the next phase of our project. Our client are keen for us to start looking at the systems that managed uploaded assets, to consolidate the different approaches into a single place and to look at switching away from a self-maintained NFS file store to something in the cloud. This sounds like an interesting mix of research, refactoring and development and we’re keen to get stuck in next week.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the meantime I spent some time documenting where we have got to in our work on Manuals Publisher with the aim of leaving some notes on how we might further refactor and improve the application. I used &lt;a href="http://plantuml.com/"&gt;plantuml&lt;/a&gt; to draw some diagrams - I still haven’t found a better tool for this kind of diagram (I really like that the source code that generates the diagram can be versioned) but it certainly feels as though the website and documentation could use some love.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We took care of a few GFR tasks including these weeknotes, invoicing and organising some of our upcoming events. I also spent a little bit of time playing with &lt;a href="http://hledger.org/"&gt;hledger&lt;/a&gt; a &lt;a href="http://plaintextaccounting.org/"&gt;plaintext accounting&lt;/a&gt; tool. I’m interested to see if we can convert our transaction history from &lt;a href="http://freeagent.com"&gt;FreeAgent&lt;/a&gt; into the &lt;a href="http://hledger.org/step-by-step.html#basic-data-entry-reporting"&gt;ledger format&lt;/a&gt; and in doing so take advantage of some of the &lt;a href="http://plaintextaccounting.org/#related-tools"&gt;tools&lt;/a&gt; in that ecosystem to do some automated reporting of our finances.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The weather in London is beautiful but wherever you are, have a great weekend.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class="footnotes"&gt; &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li id="fn:1"&gt; &lt;p&gt;The network only allows traffic over ports 80 and 443 which means accessing servers and git repositories over SSH would require some &lt;a href="https://unix.stackexchange.com/questions/190490/how-to-use-ssh-over-http-or-https"&gt;workarounds&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>week-440-links</title>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2017-06-20:/week-440-links</id>
    <updated>2017-06-20T14:39:21+01:00</updated>
    <published>2017-06-20T14:39:21+01:00</published>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-440-links" />
    <author>
      <name>james-mead</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-440---interesting-links"&gt;Week 440 - Interesting links&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;h3 id="crisp-happiness-indexhttpdnacrispsedocshappiness-indexhtml"&gt;&lt;a href="http://dna.crisp.se/docs/happiness-index.html"&gt;Crisp: Happiness Index&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Crisp are a self-organising consulting company based in Stockholm, Sweden. They use a “happiness index” as their primary metric that they use to make decisions about the direction of the company. This is very similar to an idea we’ve kicked around at &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/"&gt;Go Free Range&lt;/a&gt; from time to time. I was interested to see that they’ve split out separate scores for client and non-client work. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;JM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="pinboard-acquires-delicioushttpsblogpinboardin201706pinboardacquiresdelicious"&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.pinboard.in/2017/06/pinboard_acquires_delicious/"&gt;Pinboard acquires Delicious&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;This isn’t exactly hot off the press, but since it came as quite a surprise to me, I thought I’d mention it. As a heavy user of the original del.icio.us website, I was very sad to see what became of it after it was sold by Yahoo. Anyway, kudos to &lt;a href="http://idlewords.com/"&gt;Maciej Cegłowski&lt;/a&gt; for his relentless focus on providing &lt;a href="https://pinboard.in"&gt;the best bookmarking service&lt;/a&gt; (other than &lt;a href="https://github.com/chrisroos/roosmarks"&gt;Roosmarks&lt;/a&gt;, obviously!). &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;JM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="examples-of-governing-documents--handbooks--constitutionshttpscommunitycoopstechtexamples-of-governing-documents-handbooks-constitutions101"&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.coops.tech/t/examples-of-governing-documents-handbooks-constitutions/101"&gt;Examples of governing documents / handbooks / constitutions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ve been considering revising our company’s governing documents and potentially sharing publicly some of the wiki we use internally so that other tech co-operatives can learn from how we work. I started this thread over on the CoTech community discussion forum to collect examples from other organisations. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-lowis"&gt;CL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id="bottles-of-oophttpswwwsandimetzcom99bottles"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sandimetz.com/99bottles/"&gt;99 Bottles of OOP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’ve been working through Sandi Metz and Katrina Owen’s book “99 Bottles of OOP” in the last week. It’s a very well-written exploration of practical test-driven development and refactoring. Metz and Owen refer throughout to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Design_Patterns"&gt;design&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://martinfowler.com/books/refactoring.html"&gt;refactoring&lt;/a&gt; patterns and how they can be used to address “code smells”. This in particular made me think about our recent work refactoring an application for a client and how having a common language for describing a refactoring helps to keep individual chunks of work (for example in pull requests) self-contained. &lt;em&gt;— &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-lowis"&gt;CL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>show-and-tell-33</title>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2017-06-20:/show-and-tell-33</id>
    <updated>2017-06-20T14:03:58+01:00</updated>
    <published>2017-06-20T14:03:58+01:00</published>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-33" />
    <author>
      <name>chris-roos</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="show-and-tell-33"&gt;Show and Tell 33&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; and I were joined by &lt;a href="https://www.doc.ic.ac.uk/~rbc/"&gt;Rob C&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/robd"&gt;Rob D&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/beng"&gt;Ben G&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://chris.patuzzo.co.uk/"&gt;Chris P&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://codon.com/"&gt;Tom S&lt;/a&gt; for our 33rd Show &amp;amp; Tell.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2017-06-14-show-and-tell-33.jpg" alt="Show &amp;amp; Tell 33 drinks" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="todayomatic"&gt;Todayomatic&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Rob D’s current contract involves him doing quite a bit of remote pairing with an office-based development team. He explained the problem of trying to find availability in one of the 20+ office meeting rooms for his office-based pair to use. Each room has its own Google Calendar but the standard calendar interface doesn’t make it easy to see the availability of those rooms at a glance.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Rob’s solution is &lt;a href="https://robd.github.io/todayomatic/"&gt;Todayomatic&lt;/a&gt;: a JavaScript app that connects to your Google Calendar account to display a list of all your calendars along with their periods of availability. A text box allows you to filter the calendars on display (e.g. “meeting room”) so that you can quickly see availability of the rooms you’re interested in.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2017-06-14-show-and-tell-33-rob-d.jpg" alt="Rob D showing Todayomatic at Show &amp;amp; Tell 33" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I wondered whether Google Calendar’s Find a Time feature might be suitable but it sounds as though having to first create an event and then invite all 20+ meeting rooms means that this is less than ideal.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;James wondered whether &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/calendar/answer/190998?hl=en"&gt;Appointment Slots&lt;/a&gt; might help but no one knew too much about them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="countdown-in-the-cyber-dojo"&gt;Countdown in the Cyber Dojo&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Rob C told us about a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Countdown_(game_show)"&gt;Countdown&lt;/a&gt;-like game he co-presented with &lt;a href="http://jonjagger.blogspot.co.uk/"&gt;Jon Jagger&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href="https://conference.accu.org/site/index.html"&gt;ACCU 2017 conference&lt;/a&gt;. Jon explains the premise of the game in &lt;a href="http://jonjagger.blogspot.co.uk/2017/05/accu-c-countdown-pub-quiz.html"&gt;his blog post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the TV version, contestants play individually and have 30 seconds to find the longest word using only a small set of letters. In this version, contestants play in teams, and have ~7 minutes to write the smallest valid C++ program containing a small set of tokens.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2017-06-14-show-and-tell-33-rob-c.jpg" alt="Rob C and the Cyber Dojo at Show &amp;amp; Tell 33" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Rob has since converted the game to Ruby and we split into pairs to play a couple of rounds. Each round lasted a couple of minutes during which we had to write the smallest “valid” Ruby code that included a number of tokens. I enjoyed the challenge of trying to bend Ruby a bit in order to reduce the amount of code we had to write.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;While the Ruby solutions might be valid syntax they don’t necessarily “run” at the moment. There was some discussion afterwards about adding the requirement of having the code run in addition to being valid syntax.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="writing-an-apps-history"&gt;Writing an app’s history&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;A number of things have got Ben thinking about the information we can get from the current state of a code base:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-32#james-m---sequence-diagrams"&gt;James’s experiment in generating Sequence Diagrams from running code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;His, in his own words, unfashionable prejudice against commit comments.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;A recent experience of handing a project over to a customer and them deleting the git history in order to open source the app.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;He’s been experimenting with constructing a history based on the state of a codebase. He thinks it should be possible to order the tests in such a way as to minimise the amount of application code that needs to be added between one test and the next.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The first problem is in working out how to order the tests. His current approach is to run all the tests individually and to find the one with the lowest coverage score (i.e. it requires the smallest amount of app code to run). He repeats the process until he has all the tests ordered.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;With the tests ordered he runs each of them in turn and uses code coverage to determine the minimum amount of code required to make those tests pass. Each test and its related code is then committed to git to build some kind of “ideal” history of the app.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2017-06-14-show-and-tell-33-ben-g.jpg" alt="Ben G showing an extracted git history at Show &amp;amp; Tell 33" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben explained that the early commits contain code that doesn’t really change, followed by tests/commits that change the app code and finally code that’s untested. He’s interested in what we might learn from the “shape” of the app when viewed in this way.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben used his &lt;a href="https://github.com/techbelly/BASIC"&gt;Basic interpreter&lt;/a&gt; for this experiment. Despite the test suite being very quick to run it still takes quite a while to determine the order of tests and then to generate the history.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This reminded me a bit of James M’s &lt;a href="https://github.com/freerange/method_log"&gt;method log&lt;/a&gt; in that I think they’re both trying to extract somewhat hidden information from code.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="roombot"&gt;Roombot&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tom explained that the meeting room naming convention (famous world locations) in their new office means that people are spending/wasting time trying to work out where to go when they’re invited to meetings.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2017-06-14-show-and-tell-33-tom-s.jpg" alt="Tom S showing Roombot at Show &amp;amp; Tell 33" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tom’s built Roombot in an attempt to reduce the amount of time it takes to find the location of a meeting. Roombot sits in the company Slack channel and responds to questions about meeting room locations with a map and description of the location.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Roombot uses fuzzy matching to handle mis-spellings and is aware of alternative names for some of the locations used e.g. Ayers Rock for Uluru.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tom’s using a slight variation of the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Levenshtein_distance"&gt;Levenshtein distance&lt;/a&gt; algorithm to provide the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Approximate_string_matching"&gt;fuzzy matching&lt;/a&gt;. There are plenty of Rubygems that implement this algorithm but none of them seemed to handle this variation so &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/tomstuart/9e4fd5cd96527debf7a685d0b5399635"&gt;Tom was left to build his own&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tom didn’t want people to have to message Roombot directly which means he has to have an always-on Websocket connection so that Roombot receives the stream of all messages. He was hoping to be able to host it on a free Heroku plan but this always-on requirement meant that he had to settle for the Hobby plan instead.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He’s already had requests for additional functionality like adding support for booking rooms. Not only would this be really quite involved but he’s also happy for the app to have a single purpose and to do that one thing well.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tom’s demo of Roombot reminded me of a recent interaction in one of the GDS Slack channels. Someone asked a general question about the post room opening hours and Slackbot responded with the answer. It’s one of the very few times I’ve seen a bot used in a way that I can understand/appreciate.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="show--tell-34"&gt;Show &amp;amp; Tell 34&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’re hosting our 34th Show &amp;amp; Tell on Wednesday 12th July. Please &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/contact"&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; if you’d like to join us.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>week-439</title>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2017-06-19:/week-439</id>
    <updated>2017-06-19T15:03:31+01:00</updated>
    <published>2017-06-19T15:03:31+01:00</published>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-439" />
    <author>
      <name>james-mead</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-439"&gt;Week 439&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;This was another quiet week. Chris L’s paternity leave continued and Chris R spent some time getting his boat’s engine working so he can take it to a boatyard in a couple of weeks time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We continued work on the Manuals Publisher app for GDS, although what with one thing and another, we didn’t manage to spend loads of time on it. I continued work on the spike to identify and resolve problems which might make it hard to do the migration, and Chris R worked on actually making the required changes to manual section attachments so that their single source of truth is the Publishing API.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris R &amp;amp; I worked remotely for most of the week, but we met up at &lt;a href="https://www.theofficegroup.co.uk/office/albert-house/"&gt;TOG Albert House&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday afternoon prior to our regular &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-events"&gt;Show &amp;amp; Tell&lt;/a&gt; event that evening. We worked at &lt;a href="http://www.theofficegroup.co.uk/office/the-bloomsbury-building/"&gt;TOG Bloomsbury&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday, before Chris headed off on holiday on Friday.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For a long time, we’ve been using our own &lt;a href="https://github.com/freerange/webhooks"&gt;custom integration&lt;/a&gt; between &lt;a href="https://harmonia.io/"&gt;Harmonia&lt;/a&gt; and Trello, but on Thursday I switched us over to use the &lt;a href="https://harmonia.io/#features"&gt;official Harmonia Trello integration&lt;/a&gt;. It seems to be working well so far and hopefully it means we can retire our custom web app shortly. &lt;a href="http://lazyatom.com/"&gt;James A&lt;/a&gt; was also kind enough to implement a variation in the behaviour to support our use case, whereby archiving a card marks a task as done (i.e. no need for a “Done” list).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That’s all folks!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– James&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>week-438</title>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2017-06-19:/week-438</id>
    <updated>2017-06-19T15:02:39+01:00</updated>
    <published>2017-06-19T15:02:39+01:00</published>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-438" />
    <author>
      <name>james-mead</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-438"&gt;Week 438&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;The big news is that Chris L’s son Noah arrived on Sunday - congratulations to Chris &amp;amp; Adri!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;With Chris L on paternity leave, Chris R having some friends over on Monday afternoon, and James taking Tuesday &amp;amp; Thursday off, this was a pretty quiet week work-wise.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Early in the week, in the light of our spike into “fully migrating” the Manuals Publisher app (to use the Publisher API as its canonical persistence mechanism), we came up with an estimate for how long it would take to do this work. Later in the week, once we’d heard back from GDS, we made a start on making the changes for real.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris R spent some time investigating how to consolidate the CoTech mailing lists. For example, now that we have &lt;a href="https://community.coops.tech/"&gt;public forums&lt;/a&gt;, he thinks that the &lt;a href="https://www.email-lists.org/mailman/listinfo/tech-coops"&gt;public mailing list&lt;/a&gt; is now redundant. However, in thinking about this he got sucked into a bunch of related issues.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Friday, Chris R &amp;amp; I went to visit the Outlandish office near Finsbury Park to have a look around their nascent &lt;a href="https://www.email-lists.org/pipermail/tech-coops/2017-June/000027.html"&gt;co-working space&lt;/a&gt;. The office was understandably quiet after the General Election the night before, but Polly gave us a guided tour and explained some of their plans for the space.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Afterwards we arranged to meet up with &lt;a href="http://lazyatom.com/"&gt;James A&lt;/a&gt; for a coffee at a nearby café where we sat outside in the sunshine - it was really nice to catch-up. James then gave us a guided tour of the neighbourhood before we headed back to TOG Bloomsbury. We retired to the pub relatively early for a short retrospective, before heading our separate ways for the weekend.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Until next time!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– James&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
