<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>tag:x,2008-06-01:kind/x</id>
  <link href="http://localhost:3000" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <link href="http://localhost:3000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <title>Go Free Range Blog</title>
  <updated>2018-04-27T17:25:35+01:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-04-27:/show-and-tell-41</id>
    <published>2018-04-27T17:25:35+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-27T17:25:35+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-41" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Show and Tell 41</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-roos</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="show-and-tell-41"&gt;Show and Tell 41&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;James M&lt;/a&gt; and I were joined by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/chrispatuzzo"&gt;Chris P&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://chriszetter.com/"&gt;Chris Z&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://lazyatom.com/"&gt;James A&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://codon.com/"&gt;Tom S&lt;/a&gt; and first time attendee, &lt;a href="https://www.howlinbash.com/"&gt;Bash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="line-us"&gt;Line-us&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2018-02-23-show-and-tell-41-tom-s-hilbert-curve.jpg" alt="Tom with a Hilbert Curve" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tom S showed us his little &lt;a href="http://line-us.com/"&gt;Line-us&lt;/a&gt; drawing robot that he recently received after backing the &lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/line-us/line-us-the-little-robot-drawing-arm"&gt;product Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He showed us how to use the Line-us drawing app to control the robot before explaining how he’s been reverse engineering it to allow him to control it programmatically.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tom used &lt;a href="http://www.dns-sd.org/"&gt;DNS Service Discovery&lt;/a&gt; (DNS-SD) to find the device listening on port 1337 and then used Wireshark to inspect the traffic to and from the robot. Inspecting the traffic revealed some kind of heartbeat message being sent once per second as well as other messages that more obviously control the movement of the robot. At some point Tom realised these commands were all part of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/G-code"&gt;G-code&lt;/a&gt;, although not before he’d spent a while manually working out what they were doing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tom’s used what he learnt to write a multithreaded Ruby client that allows him to regularly send the heartbeat as well as the other commands he needs to control the arm. He demonstrated this working by instructing the arm to draw a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hilbert_curve"&gt;Hilbert Curve&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’m not sure I can necessarily think of a reason to own a Line-us but I was nevertheless impressed by Tom’s reverse engineering skills that allow him to control it programmatically.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="multiplayer-crosswords"&gt;Multiplayer crosswords&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2018-02-23-show-and-tell-41-chris-z-crossword.jpg" alt="Chris Z demonstrating his multiplayer crossword" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris Z explained that he’s been doing quite a few crosswords recently. Particularly on the Guardian. He often asks his partner for help with some of the clues and wondered whether it’d be possible to build something to allow them both to play at the same time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He discovered that the data for the Guardian crosswords (including the answers!) is stored as JSON in the page. The image is created as an SVG and the whole thing is a React component.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris found the source in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/guardian/frontend"&gt;Guardian’s frontend repository on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and managed to get it running on Heroku. He’s modified the React app to use websockets to allow multiple people to use it at the same time. He demonstrated this by having a number of us answering clues at the same time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He’s keen to share the project more widely but’s concerned that he might be violating the Guardian’s terms of service.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="generating-random-data"&gt;Generating random data&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;I spoke about using &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-gb/guide/automator/welcome/mac"&gt;Automator&lt;/a&gt; to generate data to help with manual testing during our asset manager work at GDS. I’d often find myself using the admin interface to create objects in the system and wanted a way of generating names for the things I was creating.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I started by sequentially numbering the things I was creating (e.g. “thing-1”, “thing-2”, “thing-n”) but it soon becomes hard to remember which number I was up to. I moved on to using timestamps (e.g. “2018-04-24 113700”, “2018-04-24 113730”) which were a bit better because I didn’t have to remember anything but were still a bit problematic because they’re hard to distinguish when you have a number of them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the end, I used a combination of a timestamp and a random word from the words file on my Mac. This naming convention has the advantage of conveying when the thing was created and of having a unique name that makes it easy to recognise in the short term.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="parsing-emails"&gt;Parsing emails&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;James A explained the difficulty he’s having in trying to reliably parse emails for some mailing list software he’s been working on. It might sound as though it should be a solved problem but it seems that even hosted services (e.g. &lt;a href="https://www.mailgun.com/"&gt;Mailgun&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://mailchimp.com/"&gt;Mailchimp&lt;/a&gt;) do it slightly differently and therefore it’s not completely obvious that you’d use such a service instead of writing something to parse them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="spacemacs"&gt;Spacemacs&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2018-02-23-show-and-tell-41-james-a-magit.jpg" alt="James A describing Spacemacs and magit" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;James A gave us a bit of an intro to &lt;a href="http://spacemacs.org/"&gt;Spacemacs&lt;/a&gt;. He’s switched editors a few times over the years and this is the first time in a while that he’s had some enthusiasm for one of them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;James explained that the extensive documentation and easily discoverable commands make it very easy to get started with. And that if you can see the value in Vim but have struggled to use it effectively then you might want to give Spacemacs a try.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He demonstrated the &lt;a href="https://magit.vc/"&gt;magit&lt;/a&gt; git package that provides git integration in the editor and briefly showed us his custom command/script that allows him to run &lt;code&gt;rails test&lt;/code&gt; from within the editor.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;hr /&gt; &lt;h2 id="karaoke"&gt;Karaoke&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://gofreerange.com/images/blog/2018-02-23-show-and-tell-41-bash-karaoke.jpg" alt="Bash showing his karaoke app" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Bash showed us the React karaoke app he’s building. It’s similar in style to early versions of iTunes in that it allows you to filter by Era, Genre, Artist and Song to help find the music you’re interested in. I’m not really up on the current state of karaoke but if it’s still common practice to flick through a book of hundreds of songs then I can imagine this being much easier to use.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Bash is building the app to help him learn React and to, ultimately, help him get to better karaoke parties :-)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-04-27:/week-484</id>
    <published>2018-04-27T15:52:41+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-27T15:52:41+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-484" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 484</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-roos</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-484"&gt;Week 484&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; took an impromptu week off having seen the favourable weather forecast at the end of last week.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/ben-griffiths"&gt;Ben&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-lowis"&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; and I moved into a larger 6-person office at &lt;a href="http://www.ministryofstartups.com/"&gt;Ministry of Startups&lt;/a&gt; on Monday, and have spent the week working on a project for &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/rd"&gt;BBC R&amp;amp;D&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ve got some &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/upcoming-availability"&gt;availability in the near future&lt;/a&gt; so please &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/mailto:lets@gofreerange.com"&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; if you have a project you think we can work together on.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="bbc-rd"&gt;BBC R&amp;amp;D&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;BBC R&amp;amp;D have developed a story editor and engine that allows them to create voice controlled stories (e.g. &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/rd/blog/2017-09-voice-ui-inspection-chamber-audio-drama"&gt;The Inspection Chamber&lt;/a&gt;) to run on multiple devices. They’ve asked us to explore how these stories might use information from arbitrary external services in order to make them feel more dynamic, and to come up with some demos of how this might be used.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We spent a while familiarising ourselves with the code before getting our hands dirty with some changes. Fortunately this familiarisation didn’t take too long after we’ve spent the past couple of weeks exploring and playing with voice controlled devices.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The story editor already includes the ability to branch a story based on the result of executing some arbitrary JavaScript code. We started by overloading this to return the response from an HTTP request if the code to execute looks like a URL. This allowed us to get something working without having to make changes to both the editor and the engine, and it revealed that we needed to make the engine asynchronous so that we could wait for the response from the external service. Ben updated the engine to make it use &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Guide/Using_promises"&gt;Promises&lt;/a&gt; all the way through while Chris and I paired on deploying the engine to AWS and hooking it all up so that we could interact with a story using the &lt;a href="https://developer.amazon.com/docs/devconsole/about-the-developer-console.html"&gt;Alexa Developer console&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ve finished the week with a simple game of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coin_flipping"&gt;Heads or Tails&lt;/a&gt;, authored in the story editor and running on a version of the engine that we’ve deployed to Lambda. The game asks you to choose heads or tails, makes a request to a web service that randomly chooses heads or tails and then lets you know whether you’ve won. It’s &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; simple but it gives us a good foundation to build on in order to create some more interesting demos.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Until next time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– Chris&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-04-26:/upcoming-availability</id>
    <published>2018-04-26T11:53:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-26T11:53:00+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/upcoming-availability" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Upcoming availability</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-lowis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="upcoming-availability"&gt;Upcoming availability&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;We have some availability coming up. Here’s a few ways we might be able to help you:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;We’re a team of 4 &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com#people"&gt;experienced developers&lt;/a&gt;. We’re happy &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/projects#harmonia"&gt;building new applications from scratch&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/projects#smart-answers"&gt;refactoring legacy code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;We enjoy working with existing teams and particularly coaching new developers. You might want to &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/projects#futurelearn-mooc-platform"&gt;build a team around us&lt;/a&gt; while we help you to establish good development practices.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;We prefer to work in an agile way. We can show you how that works and work with you to adopt agile practices.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Give us a problem to solve - we love &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/projects"&gt;creative projects&lt;/a&gt; and prototyping.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Our favourite language is Ruby and we’re happy to work on Rails projects. We can also turn our hand to JavaScript and iOS development. We’ve worked on web applications, data-processing systems, 3D graphics, voice-controlled applications including the Alexa, video- and audio-processing tools, data science and more. We love a challenge.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you think we might be able to work together &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/mailto:lets@gofreerange.com"&gt;drop us a line&lt;/a&gt; and we’ll arrange to meet you for a cuppa.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-04-20:/show-and-tell-43</id>
    <published>2018-04-20T11:43:26+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-20T11:43:26+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-43" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Show and Tell 43</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-lowis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="show-and-tell-43"&gt;Show and Tell 43&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;We had a good attendance at our Show &amp;amp; Tell event this week with &lt;a href="https://www.howlinbash.com/"&gt;Bash&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/ben-griffiths"&gt;Ben&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://codon.com/"&gt;Tom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;James&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://makercasts.org/"&gt;Chris P&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://chriszetter.com/"&gt;Chris Z&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-lowis"&gt;myself&lt;/a&gt; getting together to share our side projects and offer friendly feedback.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="porting-classic-text-adventure-games-to-amazons-alexa"&gt;Porting classic text adventure games to Amazon’s Alexa&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben showed us a project he’s been working on during his first week at Go Free Range. We have a client project coming up that will involve working with voice controlled devices. Ben thought he’d learn a bit more about this technology by attempting to implement a classic text adventure game.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Classic text adventure games, such as those from Infocom, were written to run on a virtual machine called the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Z-machine"&gt;Z-machine&lt;/a&gt;. Writing the games for this abstract machine made it easier to port them to various computer platforms as the virtual machine only needed to be written once per platform in order to run multiple games.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Z-machine has subsequently been reverse engineered and implemented in many languages. Ben based his work on a &lt;a href="https://github.com/wilkie/gruesome"&gt;Ruby implementation&lt;/a&gt;. The text adventure accepts commands, such as “Go North” or “Look” and returns information about the world&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt; West of House This is an open field west of a white house, with a boarded front door. There is a small mailbox here. A rubber mat saying 'Welcome to Zork!' lies by the door. &lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Additionally the state of the game can be mutated. For example when a player picks something up and adds it to their inventory.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben made &lt;a href="https://github.com/freerange/gruesome/commits/feature/stateless_execution"&gt;some changes&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;code&gt;gruesome&lt;/code&gt; to allow it to run on as a web service. A Sinatra-based &lt;a href="https://github.com/freerange/gruesome/commit/b1948f970f168e05defb329953fe2505d9af797c#diff-0932482613b47f8170071b9df96e02a5"&gt;application&lt;/a&gt; accepts a command and returns the output of the game and the current state of the virtual machine serialised as a string. When a new command is issued, the previous state is passed along with the request so that the web server itself can operate without maintaining any state of its own.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-roos"&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt;’s help this web service was then connected to an Amazon &lt;a href="https://github.com/freerange/alexa-lambda-gruesome"&gt;lambda function&lt;/a&gt; which could be called from an Alexa application (or “skill”).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben demo’d the game and it worked much better at Show and Tell than it had in the GFR office last week! Ben talked about how voice-controlled devices, while on the surface feeling like a natural fit for this kind of game, have quite a few problems. The speech-to-text isn’t quite good enough pass directly to the original game engine, as these game engines perform exact matches from a pre-prepared dictionary of commands.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt; &amp;gt; jog north That's not a verb I recognise. &amp;gt; trot north That's not a verb I recognise. &amp;gt; amble north That's not a verb I recognise. &amp;gt; walk north North of House You are facing the north side of a white house. There is no door here, and all the windows are barred. &lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben investigated extracting the list of verbs and objects recognised from an individual game using a Z-code disassembler called &lt;a href="http://inform-fiction.org/zmachine/ztools.html"&gt;infodump&lt;/a&gt;. Potentially this output could be used to generate some training examples for the Alexa skill’s &lt;a href="https://developer.amazon.com/docs/custom-skills/create-intents-utterances-and-slots.html"&gt;Intent Parser&lt;/a&gt; but it still feels like there would need to be some considerable modification to the game-play mechanics to make these games playable using voice commands alone.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="compact-encoding-of-permutations"&gt;Compact encoding of permutations&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://makercasts.org/"&gt;Chris Patuzzo&lt;/a&gt; recently gave &lt;a href="https://skillsmatter.com/skillscasts/11694-london-ruby-user-group-april"&gt;a talk&lt;/a&gt; at the London Ruby User Group about Sliding Puzzles. He gave us a &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-42"&gt;preview of that talk&lt;/a&gt; at the last Show &amp;amp; Tell.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris wanted to show us an approach he’d taken to compactly storing the various permutations a sliding puzzle could be in. It turns out that efficiently solving a sliding puzzle requires storing a huge amount of data for all the possible permutations of the puzzle in memory. The more compactly these permutations can be stored the better.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris showed us an example of a puzzle:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt; | 5 | 1 | 2 | | 3 | 4 | x | | 0 | 6 | 7 | &lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;where each tile in the puzzle is sequentially numbered and &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; is the blank space that another tile can be slid to. A simple way to store this puzzle state is as the number &lt;code&gt;51234067&lt;/code&gt;. But we can do better than that.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;First we compute the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lehmer_code"&gt;Lehmer Code&lt;/a&gt; for the permutation. We do this by considering each number in the permutation from left to right and asking “how many numbers to the left of this number are greater than the current number?”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;5&lt;/b&gt;1234067 - &lt;b&gt;0&lt;/b&gt; numbers greater to the left of this one &lt;br /&gt; 5&lt;b&gt;1&lt;/b&gt;234067 - &lt;b&gt;1&lt;/b&gt; number greater to the left of this one &lt;br /&gt; 51&lt;b&gt;2&lt;/b&gt;34067 - &lt;b&gt;1&lt;/b&gt; number greater to the left of this one &lt;br /&gt; 512&lt;b&gt;3&lt;/b&gt;4067 - &lt;b&gt;1&lt;/b&gt; number greater to the left of this one &lt;br /&gt; 5123&lt;b&gt;4&lt;/b&gt;067 - &lt;b&gt;1&lt;/b&gt; number greater to the left of this one &lt;br /&gt; 51234&lt;b&gt;0&lt;/b&gt;67 - &lt;b&gt;5&lt;/b&gt; numbers greater to the left of this one &lt;br /&gt; 512340&lt;b&gt;6&lt;/b&gt;7 - &lt;b&gt;0&lt;/b&gt; numbers greater to the left of this one &lt;br /&gt; 5123406&lt;b&gt;7&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;b&gt;0&lt;/b&gt; numbers greater to the left of this one &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The resulting number, &lt;code&gt;01111500&lt;/code&gt; in this case, is the Lehmer-encoded representation of &lt;code&gt;51234067&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We can compress this number even further by encoding it in the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Factorial_number_system"&gt;Factorial Number System&lt;/a&gt;. This number system is similar to how we encode numbers in any base, but uses factorial numbers as the base. For example the number 362 in base ten is “3 hundreds, 6 tens and 2 ones” or&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt; (3*100) + (6*10) + (2*1) = 362 &lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;That same number in a factorial base would be&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt; (3*2!) + (6*1!) + (2*0!) = 14 &lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;and our Lehmer encoded permutation &lt;code&gt;01111500&lt;/code&gt; in factorial base is&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt; (0*7!) + (1*6!) + (1*5!) + (1*4!) + (1*3!) + (5*2!) + (0*1!) + (0*0!) = 880 &lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;which is a more compact way of representing the number &lt;code&gt;51234067&lt;/code&gt;. This original permutation code can be recovered from the number &lt;code&gt;880&lt;/code&gt; by following the process in reverse.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris showed us that the naive algorithm for performing Lehmer encoding given above has &lt;code&gt;O(n^2)&lt;/code&gt; complexity and is therefore prohibitive to use in practice. However there does exist a linear-time version of the algorithm that relies on bit-shifting and the &lt;a href="http://www.felixcloutier.com/x86/POPCNT.html"&gt;POPCNT&lt;/a&gt; instruction. &lt;a href="https://github.com/tuzz/lehmer/blob/master/src/lib.rs#L9"&gt;Chris has implemented this in Rust&lt;/a&gt; but we didn’t have time to dig into that code.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="keeping-notes-in-plain-text"&gt;Keeping notes in plain text&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Bash showed us his system for keeping notes about what to work on and what he’s learned.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He wrote a &lt;a href="https://github.com/howlinbash/dotfiles/blob/master/.bashrc.d/functions.sh#L18"&gt;shell function &lt;code&gt;log&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to create a log book. This creates a new file in a daily logs directory and copies the contents of the previous days log into it. This allows Bash to keep track of what is changing day-to-day and base today’s notes on what was left over from the previous day.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Having found this useful, Bash wanted to create a similar system for keeping to-do lists. He showed us some Vimscript he’d written to configure his editor to manage these to-do lists.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the todo file are entries such as&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt; - 201804191200 x eat Have Lunch - 201804191429 wri Write-up notes from Show and Tell &lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Each entry includes a timestamp, an indication of the status of the todo item, an optional tag and the task description. Various editor commands allow these properties to be toggled, and filtered.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Bash also wrote a command to create a new files based on the timestamp and quickly jump to them. This allows notes about each todo item to be kept and conveniently indexed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This idea of hyper-linking from the to-do list to notes also inspired Bash to use a personal Wiki to keep notes. He showed us &lt;a href="https://github.com/vimwiki/vimwiki"&gt;Vimwiki&lt;/a&gt;, which implements a wiki system inside of Vim, and his &lt;a href="https://github.com/howlinbash/manual"&gt;personal “manual”&lt;/a&gt; containing notes on the software he regularly uses and new things he has learnt. I particularly enjoyed the &lt;a href="https://github.com/howlinbash/how"&gt;script &lt;code&gt;how&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; he’d written to review items that had recently been added to his wiki. When he’s happy he’s remembered the particular fact, he removes it from this automatically generated “to learn” list.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="writing-a-game-for-the-amazon-alexa"&gt;Writing a game for the Amazon Alexa&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;At the end of the meeting James, Ben and I talked briefly about a follow-up project to the one Ben showed us earlier in the evening. We’ve decided that doing a straight port of a text adventure game to a voice-controlled device isn’t optimum in terms of the capabilities of these devices. Instead we’re building a simple game from scratch with voice-control in mind.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The prototype we showed involves giving directions to a ship lost at sea using only audio clues from the environment around you (the sounds of crashing waves, bell-buoys and lighthouse horns). Chris and Zetter had a quick play-test of the game. We were encouraged by the moments of shared confusion (“Did I hear a bell?”) and the fact that they quickly picked up the game mechanics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There’ll be some more detail about this in our weeknotes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;!-- add content here --&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-04-17:/week-471</id>
    <published>2018-04-17T12:00:48+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-17T12:00:48+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-471" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 471</title>
    <author>
      <name>james-mead</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-471"&gt;Week 471&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that I’m writing these notes about 3 months late - sorry!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris R and I worked in various TOG offices and Space4 this week with Chris L continuing to work remotely.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="asset-management"&gt;Asset Management&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We had our usual catch-up meeting with Daniel on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This week we finally managed to migrate all of the non-attachment assets from Whitehall to Asset Manager and started serving them from Asset Manager. We also started spiking on supporting attachment assets from Whitehall in Asset Manager and in particular requiring authorisation for attachments on draft documents.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’ve spent quite a while helping diagnose problems in the new AWS-based integration environment and continued to suffer from problems with it, although now the problems were to do with failures in the overnight sync-ing of assets from the production environment, rather than problems with the environment itself.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="gfr"&gt;GFR&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Wednesday Chris R gave &lt;a href="https://github.com/freerange/cotech-presentation"&gt;a presentation about GFR&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/London-CoTech-Meetup/events/246674795/"&gt;the inaugural CoTech Monthly Meet-up&lt;/a&gt;, “Discover why we chose to own our companies, and how they work!”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He talked about the history of GFR, our company structure, the tools and processes we use to run the company without a boss, and the benefits and challenges of working the way we do. I think Chris did an excellent job, but you can judge for yourself in the video!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;video class="video-js vjs-default-skin vjs-big-play-centered" controls="" preload="none" height="400" width="600" poster="http://videos.gofreerange.com/5872d4c4/480p-00001.png" data-setup="{}"&gt; &lt;source src="http://videos.gofreerange.com/5872d4c4/480p.mp4" type="video/mp4" /&gt; &lt;source src="http://videos.gofreerange.com/5872d4c4/480p.webm" type="video/webm" /&gt; &lt;/video&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Friday we held our usual company meeting in a TOG meeting room with Chris L participating remotely via &lt;a href="https://appear.in/"&gt;appear.in&lt;/a&gt; on the big screen which seems to work well for us.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That’s all folks!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– James&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-04-13:/week-482</id>
    <published>2018-04-13T14:20:36+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-13T14:20:36+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-482" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 482</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-lowis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-482"&gt;Week 482&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hello! This week we moved into our new office, Ben had his first full week as a Go Free Range member and we took some time to learn and work on a side project.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="new-office"&gt;New Office&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We recently took a 4-person office in a &lt;a href="https://www.ministryofstartups.com/"&gt;Ministry of Startups&lt;/a&gt;-run building on Turner Street in Whitechapel. We’d being paying £375/month for our co-working desks at The Office Group and while having access to their very well maintained buildings across London was a definite plus, the costs started to add up when we considered having a fourth membership. Ministry of Startups say:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’re real, We’re honest, We’re not perfect. (But we definitely know what startups actually need from a coworking space)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Our 4-person office is partitioned from a larger open warehouse-like space on the top floor of a building. We have great natural light and views over the city, solid desks, access to a small kitchen, a quiet working environment and fast, reliable wifi. We’ve been here every day this week so far, and are happy with the £225/desk/month price.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This seems like a good base for now while we consider looking for something more conveniently located for all of us. If you happen to be in the Whitechapel Area, get in touch and pop by for a cuppa.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="welcome-ben"&gt;Welcome Ben&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben had his first day with us in the office on Monday and during the week we have been getting him set up with accounts on the various systems we use (Trello, Harmonia, Google, Heroku, AWS etc.). We also added him to our online banking and made sure he was included in our payroll and auto-enrolment pension contributions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When I joined GFR this time last year it had been quite a long time since anyone had joined and we took the opportunity to document some of the things we needed to do. I think that documentation came in handy this time but there’s still a lot of manual work to be done - and frustratingly, paper forms to print and send by post.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It’s great to have Ben in the team and when the &lt;a href="https://harmonia.io/"&gt;Harmonia&lt;/a&gt; gods smile upon him you’ll hear from him in our weeknotes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="voice-controlled-devices"&gt;Voice-controlled devices&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’re between client projects this week so we thought we’d take some time out to learn about voice-controlled “virtual assistants”. These services, for example Apple’s Siri, Amazon’s Alexa or Google’s Assistant are accessed via smartphone or desktop applications, or through dedicated hardware such as the Alexa or Google Home. We have a few of these types of devices to hand and thought it would be fun to play around with them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The task we set ourselves at the beginning of the week was to see if we could port an &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Z-machine"&gt;Infocom-style text adventure game&lt;/a&gt; to a voice-controlled assistant.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We started by surveying some of the technology that is available. I read through the &lt;a href="https://developer.amazon.com/alexa-skills-kit"&gt;documentation and tutorials&lt;/a&gt; for the Alexa system, while Chris spent some time looking at the &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/actions/"&gt;Google Assistant&lt;/a&gt;. Meanwhile Ben investigated &lt;a href="https://dialogflow.com/"&gt;Dialogflow&lt;/a&gt;, an abstraction service that allows applications to be deployed to multiple assistant platforms.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In order to learn a bit more about the technology we decided to build a simple application first. At Go Free Range we often assign card on our trello board to one of us at random. We thought we’d build a voice-controlled application to do this. By Wednesday we had something working on Google Assistant and Alexa.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Developing an Alexa application, or “skill” involves two phases. Firstly the skill is registered in the Alexa developer console. Here we choose a name, define a series of commands (known as “intents”) and provide some sample phrases to trigger those intents. For an example, a conversation with our Go Free Range Helper skill might go like:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt; &amp;gt; Me: Alexa, ask the Go Free Range Helper to choose someone &amp;gt; Alexa: Chris L is the chosen one &amp;gt; Me: Choose someone else &amp;gt; Alexa: Ben is the chosen one &lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;The command to “choose someone” results in some JSON like&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt; 'request': { 'locale': 'en-US', 'type': 'IntentRequest', 'intent': { 'name': 'assignment' } } &lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;being sent to a application that can be accessed at an end point defined in the skill configuration. The application responds with the text to be spoken which is then read out by Alexa. Amazon suggest to use their “serverless” &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/lambda/"&gt;Lambda&lt;/a&gt; platform to run the application, but it is also possible to use any application accessible over HTTPS.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We wrote a &lt;a href="https://github.com/freerange/alexa-helper"&gt;simple nodejs application&lt;/a&gt; to handle the logic of the application. We also spent some time learning how to deploy Lambda applications using the &lt;a href="https://github.com/serverless/serverless"&gt;Serverless Framework&lt;/a&gt; and test it using &lt;a href="https://facebook.github.io/jest/"&gt;Jest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris R also implemented the same application for the Google Assistant platform using &lt;a href="https://dialogflow.com/"&gt;Dialogflow&lt;/a&gt; to write and deploy the application. Here’s a video of it being tested using the developer tools in Dialogflow:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;video class="video-js vjs-default-skin vjs-big-play-centered" controls="" preload="none" height="400" width="600" poster="http://videos.gofreerange.com/d4bb42b2/480p-00001.png" data-setup="{}"&gt; &lt;source src="http://videos.gofreerange.com/d4bb42b2/480p.mp4" type="video/mp4" /&gt; &lt;source src="http://videos.gofreerange.com/d4bb42b2/480p.webm" type="video/webm" /&gt; &lt;/video&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Towards the end of the week, having got a grasp on the development process and terminology, we started to work on our more sophisticated application idea - porting a text adventure game to Alexa. Ben investigated several implementations of the “z-machine” interpreter that allows popular text adventure games to be run. He settled on &lt;a href="https://github.com/freerange/gruesome"&gt;this Ruby implementation&lt;/a&gt; and set about modifying it to work with our proposed architecture. This involved modifying the code to allow the state to be serialised and reloaded, which will allow our Alexa application to keep track of where a player is in the game. He also added a Sinatra-based API to the engine so that it could be played using HTTP.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As I write, Chris is hooking up this game engine to a new Alexa Skill. If we decide to carry on with this side-project next week, we’ll have more to show you then.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Until next time!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;!-- add content here --&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-04-06:/week-481</id>
    <published>2018-04-06T17:38:30+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-06T17:38:30+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-481" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 481</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-roos</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-481"&gt;Week 481&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;Afternoon folks.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It’s a beautiful day here today: it finally feels a bit like Spring after some very cold and wet days.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; rejoined us on Tuesday after his week away and after we’d all enjoyed the long Easter weekend break.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We spent Tuesday and Wednesday working on the GDS &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/asset-manager"&gt;Asset Manager&lt;/a&gt; project before finally finishing up and handing over yesterday. I have slightly mixed feelings about handing it over: having a break from the work is very welcome but I’m disappointed that we didn’t get as much done as we’d have liked. Unfortunately the budget wouldn’t allow us to continue but I’m hopeful that we’ve done a good enough job of documenting what we’ve done so that the GOV.UK team can continue the work to get the remaining &lt;a href="http://github.com/alphagov/whitehall"&gt;Whitehall&lt;/a&gt; attachments served by Asset Manager.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Our other big news of the week is that &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/beng"&gt;Ben Griffiths&lt;/a&gt; has joined us as our newest member. James and I have both worked with Ben in the past (James and Ben at &lt;a href="https://www.thoughtworks.com/"&gt;Thoughtworks&lt;/a&gt; and James, Ben and I at &lt;a href="https://www.reevoo.com/"&gt;Reevoo&lt;/a&gt;) and he’s been a friend of GFR since the beginning. Since leaving Reevoo Ben’s been involved in numerous startups and has most recently been working at &lt;a href="https://www.dxw.com/"&gt;DXW&lt;/a&gt;. We’re all really happy to have Ben join and are looking forward to seeing what this means for us.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ben’s official start date is today but we’ve all agreed to take it a bit easier today and to welcome Ben properly on Monday.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Until next time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– Chris&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-03-29:/week-480</id>
    <published>2018-03-29T17:38:41+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-29T17:38:41+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-480" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 480</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-roos</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-480"&gt;Week 480&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;Howdi folks&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/james-mead"&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; is taking a well-earned break this week. &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/chris-lowis"&gt;Chris&lt;/a&gt; and I have worked from &lt;a href="http://www.theofficegroup.co.uk/"&gt;TOG&lt;/a&gt; Whitechapel, TOG Bloomsbury and from home.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Looking at the office in Hoxton last week made us wonder what else was available. A friend suggested we look at &lt;a href="http://www.ministryofstartups.com/"&gt;Ministry of Startups&lt;/a&gt;. We got in touch and were able to view a couple of their Whitechapel properties on Monday. The offices look just about perfect for what we’re after and they’re &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; competitively priced so we’re planning to take one on. We’ve notified TOG that we’d like to cancel our memberships.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We’re coming to the end of our time on the &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/asset-manager"&gt;Asset Manager&lt;/a&gt; project and have a final handover session arranged for Thursday next week. We ran the metadata update in production earlier this week but then suffered a number of setbacks that have further delayed us being able to switch to serving &lt;a href="http://github.com/alphagov/whitehall"&gt;Whitehall&lt;/a&gt; attachments from Asset Manager. We’ll have to see how much we can do on Tuesday and Wednesday before the handover.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris published the &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/show-and-tell-42"&gt;write-up of our Show &amp;amp; Tell event from last week&lt;/a&gt; as well as &lt;a href="http://gofreerange.com/week-479"&gt;weeknotes for last week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chris also helped get the &lt;a href="https://community.coops.tech/t/cotech-newsletter-march-2018/685"&gt;CoTech March newsletter&lt;/a&gt; published.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’ve ordered a laptop for our new member. He joins us on the 6th of April so we’ll be able to share who it is next week.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Harmonia chose me to donate to charity this month and I chose &lt;a href="https://www.nct.org.uk/"&gt;NCT&lt;/a&gt;. My partner and I are expecting our first child and have been making use of the great NCT classes available.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Until next time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;– Chris&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-03-29:/week-477</id>
    <published>2018-03-29T15:55:35+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-29T15:55:35+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-477" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 477</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-lowis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-477"&gt;Week 477&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;I returned from an extended trip to Colombia this week and in my jet-lagged state never got round to writing weeknotes. These come to you, therefore, almost 3 weeks late!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Looking back through my notes I see we spent a couple of days in the Bloomsbury Office Group office, held our monthly drinks at The Three Crowns and continued to work on our Asset Manager project for GDS.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="asset-manager"&gt;Asset Manager&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We are trying to move the last remaining files (around 500,000 attachments) from the Whitehall publishing application to Asset Manager. In doing so we need to make sure that Whitehall no longer depends on files existing on the file system as once we’ve made the switch the files will leave in Amazon’s cloud storage service S3.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One area we’d overlooked was the functionality to preview a CSV which is used to give an overview of data files before a user commits to downloading a potentially large file. For very large files the code was using ruby’s low-level &lt;code&gt;File&lt;/code&gt; API to read in a limited number of bytes of the file from disk. &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/whitehall/pull/3826"&gt;We changed this to use a HTTP RANGE request instead&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We also had to make sure that metadata about each attachment that was previously stored in Whitehall is now stored in Asset Manager. This includes &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/asset-manager/pull/502"&gt;support for parent document URLs in HTTP headers&lt;/a&gt;. In addition we &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/asset-manager/pull/512"&gt;continued to add support&lt;/a&gt; for access-limited and draft assets to Asset Manager.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Warm greetings from the future!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;!-- add content here --&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:gofreerange.com,2018-03-29:/week-479</id>
    <published>2018-03-29T15:42:39+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-29T15:42:39+01:00</updated>
    <link href="http://gofreerange.com/week-479" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Week 479</title>
    <author>
      <name>chris-lowis</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="week-479"&gt;Week 479&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;This week we were mostly finishing up our work on the Asset Manager project. We took some time away from that to do a little bit of office-hunting and to do our quarterly “away-day”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="asset-management"&gt;Asset Management&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We were mostly preparing to switch serving attachments from Whitehall to Asset Manager by:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/whitehall/pull/3881"&gt;Refactoring the related controllers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/whitehall/pull/3892"&gt;Writing a worker&lt;/a&gt; to handle the migration of metadata&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/whitehall/pull/3903"&gt;Landing a few changes&lt;/a&gt; from a long-running branch onto &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/whitehall/pull/3880"&gt;Dealing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/asset-manager/pull/528"&gt;with&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/alphagov/asset-manager/pull/531"&gt;edge cases&lt;/a&gt; present in the 500,000 assets we’re attempting to migrate.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;By the end of the week we’d reached the point where we could start running the migration to make sure that all of the assets in Asset Manager had the same draft, redirect and access-limited metadata as they do in Whitehall. Once we’ve ironed out all the inconsistencies we’ll finally make a change to the nginx server and start serving traffic.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="office-hunting"&gt;Office Hunting&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We have a new member joining in early April which will take Go Free Range up to 4 permanent members. We’re currently using co-working membership at The Office Group. While we’ve been happy with the flexibility this offers there’s a couple of downsides that will get worse when we’re 4. Firstly, it’s quite difficult to find 4 desks next to each other in our preferred co-working space. This is understandable, they’re really designed for individual workers not teams. Secondly, at £375 per desk per month it starts to look financially more sensible to look for some permanent desks somewhere.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We certainly miss having our own office - we used to be able to host people for short stays working with us, have clients over, and host evening events in our old place on Worship St. With rents steadily climbing though, this may not be possible again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This week we took a look at some sub-let desks in a spacious building in Hoxton. We’re going to keep looking for something flexible and keep thinking about a slightly more permanent home for the future.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id="away-day"&gt;Away Day&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;We like to get away from the day-to-day work once every 3 months ago and talk about something a bit higher level. This time we spent a couple of hours in a The Office Group meeting room near Bank station, before having a long lunch. On the agenda was our pay and renumeration for the next financial year, our on-going work to change our articles of association and become a legit co-operative and our hopes and aspirations for the coming year with a new member joining.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A particularly interesting discussion was around time-tracking and holidays. We have an informal “take as many days off as you need” policy, but we’re a little worried that we’re not taking the breaks we need when we’re busy, and that without a firmer policy we might be feeling guilty taking time off when others are not. We discussed tracking time worked and time off more closely but felt unsure about the unintended consequences of doing that. We decided to have a standing agenda item in our weekly meetings where we talk about time worked, time taken off, what our work-life balance is like and anything we can change to improve it. We hope that by forcing ourselves to discuss this more regularly it’ll be easier to make small changes to improve things.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;‘Til next time!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;!-- add content here --&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
